Hey, Richard.
Never mind.
What do you mean, never mind? I called your name.
With a tone.
All right, come on.
I'll give you voluntary.
Make it involuntary, you have a deal.
I can't.
Richard.
I've got marching orders.
Remember this thing was on tape.
We've got public outcry to deal with.
Public outcry? The public is with her.
Ellenor, I'm giving you manslaughter for a premeditated murder.
Why can't you ever take a gift and smile?
It is a good deal, Sally.
They only possible defense we have is temporary insanity.
And because you don't want to say that you were insane...
I wasn't.
Well, then I think that we should jump at manslaughter.
You will probably be sentenced to eight years.
And with any luck, you'd only have to serve three or four.
Sally, you shot an unarmed man.
If somebody raped and murdered my daughter,
I might have done the same thing.
But the problem is you planed it.
If we go for a not guilty on the elements,
you could be going to prison for life.
Take the manslaughter.
No.
Sally.
Ok.
So the trial will start tomorrow.
Guard.
Ok, we're gonna see you at the court house.
听写 时间轴：美溪客
How could she not take it?
She doesn't want to serve three years...
So she'll be serving life if she doesn't accept.
Bobby, I told her that, so did Jimmy.
She wants to try to beat it.
Did you tell her the odds?
Yes, we did.
So, what are you arguing? Insanity?
No, unfortunately, she doesn't want to do that either.
Who is in charge here?
She is, she is the client, remember?
And you're her lawyer which means you need to make her understand...
Bobby, don't lecture me.
Judge Hiller is sitting, she won't let you argue nullification,
you know she won't.
Have we got a phychiatrist to say she was insane?
I got doctor Thibodeau stand by.
I'm telling you, she will not let us do it.
Ellenor, this thing is all over the news.
Which means if Sally Berg goes down on murder one,
We'll be played for the idiots, not her.
Oh, so, this is about our ego?
Partly is. But it goes with her best interests.
You go back to her and make her see if she doesn't plead insanity...
We tried.
Try again.
If she refuses, file a motion to withdraw as counsel.
Bobby, this is just like our rabbi case,
maybe we could argue moral duress again.
No, Jimmy, because this time, we have judge Hiller.
Go back to the client,
she either takes manslaugher, pleads insanity,
or we withdraw.
Hey, Sally.
All right, listen,
As much as you oppose it on prinple,
we all agreed that if we're gonna go to trial,
we have to go with temporary insanity.
The only other choice we have
is jury nullification.
And that judge will shut us down in a second.
But if we win on temporary, you could avoid prison altogether.
You have a chance, but you have to let us do our job.
If we're to give you the best representation...
What did she say?
She just called me a bitch.
Look,
I don't need you, and I don't need this case.
You could get life, I don't really care.
He killed my baby.
Let me do my job, let me do my job.
What? What's going on?
We're pleading temporary insanity.
Richard.
Helen.
To what do I owe this?
Ah, well, actually,
I was just assigned second chair.
Excuse me?
It's getting a lot of heat, so...
They put you on to, what, backstop me?
I asked to be put on it.
Why?
Well,
Helen, what's going on?
What's going on is...
you're a little under review.
What do you mean I'm under review?
You've dropped some big trials and in addition to losing these cases,
you've also lost your poise.
especially against Ellenor Frutt.
Richard, it's an election year.
There could be some changes.
You don't want this one getting away from you, trust me.
So you...you asked to be put on
because I could lose my job?
It hasn't come to that,
but we don't want it to.
There isn't a DA in this department
who goes in more prepared than I do
every single trial.
I know that. But...
You've had some pretty high profile defeats and,
you've been somewhat a loose canon.
Richard, let's just win this.
390 people?
It's not my fault.
You invited 390 people to our wedding?
I didn't invite them.
The idiot at the stationary shop made the mistake.
There were two lists.
One was just the notice of our marriage after the wedding
She sent invitations to both lists!
What's going on?
390 people got invited to our wedding.
So what do we do now? Uninvite them?
Send out a notice, "Hey, we never meant to include you."
It wasn't my fault!
Lindsay, you were in charge of this.
Only because you couldn't be bothered.
I couldn't even get you to look at the invitations.
Oh, this is my fault?
Well it isn't mine.
You want to get married, but I have to do all of the planning.
Hey, if it were up to me, we'd elope.
You know what, you plan it.
390 people, I don't even know 390 people!
I think you both are acting out.
Stay out of it.
We had just taken Mr. Whittier under custody.
Where was that?
At his own house.
And as we were leaving the dwelling,
I observed Ms. Berg approached from acrossed the street.
What happened next, officer?
My partner and both instructed her not to approach,
but she kept coming.
Then suddenly she's raising her gun,
saying something about her daughter.
This woman right here?
Yes.
We then reached for our own weapons, but it was too late.
Your honor, at this time, we'd like to play the videotape.
Go ahead, Mr. Bay.
This arrest of course has been anticipated since early this morning when..
Um, this is Michael Whittier,
he is in custody.
You see him there in the middle,
and he's apparently offering no resistence.
Michael Whittier was...
Ok, at this time I'd like to direct your attention
to the right side of the screen.
This happens pretty quickly.
again, a suspect in the rape and murder of seven-year-old Jessica Berg,
Rumors of his arrest have been in...
He's been shot!
Michael Whittier has just been shot.
Someone has fired.
I know I heard at least two shots.
But he is down.
Michael Whittier has just been shot.
The police have the shooter, but I can't see...
He has been shot.
Officer Finlay, do you see in the courtroom the person who fired those shots?
It was the defendant.
Bobby. I don't mean to be nosy, but
You don't mean to be nosy? Since when?
Look. Obviously you two are fighting.
We're not fighting.
Well, she's fighting.
But you're just not involved enough to realize it.
Lucy, I think you should just stay out of things, is that possible?
Foley depo.
Thank you.
We go in for our marriage license today.
Did you manage to remember that?
Yes.
Good.
What is your problem?
Problem? I don't have a problem.
Look, Lindsay, you screwed up the invitations.
-Not me.-Maybe if I had a little help.
Here we go.
Don't "here we go" me.
I have had to do everything, Bobby.
You know, I had to make the lists
First you complain that I was booking everything
I meant the church and your dead mother's dress.
But when it comes to doing the real work, you just can't be bothered.
Well, I'm bothered now.
I don't think you even want to be married.
Here we go!!
Don't "here we go" me!
If you "here we go" me one more time I am going to scream, okay?
Do you hear me?
Listen to yourself!
Ooh, and I hate that one too. Listen to yourself.
"Here we go" and "Listen to yourself".
If you ever say those in our marriage, I will scream!! Okay?
It’s good to know these things before we become husband and wife.
You know, this is very, very healthy!
Bug off!
Well. It's nice to know you can make her scream.
As you can see, we were back far enough.
There she's getting out of her car.
She's got something in her coat.
She's moving across the street.
The police were all on the street, so there's no one stop her.
Ok, here it comes.
She pulls up the weapon, bang, bang.
She drops the weapon, and puts her hands up.
And she's tackled by the officers.
That's pretty much it.
What do you mean you can't tesitify?
Look, I didn't think she was insane to begin with.
I was prepared to say she might have been.
So, what's changed?
That tape I just saw.
I haven't seen it before.
And clearly, she is calm, composed.
That doesn't mean she wasn't in a rage.
Maybe she was,
but you're asking me to testify she couldn't distinguish right from wrong.
I can't say that.
She put her hands up over her head,
very calmly after she fired those shots.
That tells me she expected to be arrested.
It tells me she knew what she was doing was wrong.
Oh, come on.
This defense was a stretch to begin with, Ellenor.
I can't stretch it that far.
You have before.
No, I haven't, Eugene.
And certainly not on television.
I have a professional reputation too,
you ever think about that?
Think about it, we're paying you for it.
We gave you 10000 dollars.
I'll refund the money.
You can't jump ship like this.
I'm not about to commit perjury.
And if I testified I thought your client was temporary insane,
I would be doing so.
If you don't testify, she could be facing life.
Your client committed murder, Ellenor.
You don't want to be introducing my opinion.
Now what?
We got doctor Lanning.
Doctor dope?
At least he'll say what we want.
This is just great.
I think I should take her cross.
Why?
No offense, but I just think I'm able to come off more sympathetic than you.
You? Sympathetic?
Richard, it's a woman on trial, she lost her daughter.
I just think it makes more sense to have a woman cross her.
On the other side, I think I can go softer than you,
it's not your strength.
How close am I to losing my job, Helen?
I didn't say you were about to lose your job.
Just the game, under review.
Let's just forget about ego,
let's just concentrate on getting this conviction.
And your social security?
062-36-0749.
Okay. First marriage for both?
Yes.
Fine.
And do we have copies of our blood tests?
Uh, excellent. Okay.
This is an AIDS education pamphlet
which I'm required under Massachusetts law to give to you.
Fine.
Okay, I just need $25 in cash.
Excellent.
Okay, here you go.
Have a wonderful marriage.
She had been missing for two days when I got the call from the police.
The call?
They said they thought they'd found my daughter.
And they asked if I would go to the coroner's office
to identify her.
And did you go?
Yes.
They took me into a room,
and showed me her body.
And she was dead?
Yes.
Did you make the identification?
Do you have any other children, Sally?
No.
And Jessica's father?
He died three years ago.
At some point, you became aware
that Mr. Whittier was a suspect in Jessica's death?
Yes.
I saw it on the morning news.
That his psychiatrist had turned him in,
and the police were planning to arrest him.
Had you ever met Mr. Whittier before?
Yes.
He was Jessica's soccer coach.
I would like for you to tell the court
what happened on that morning.
I took my gun,
I, drove to his house,
I saw that the police were already there.
I parked my car two houses away.
And I waited.
Waited for what?
For him to come out.
Why?
So I could kill him.
Can you tell the court
what you were thinking when you approached him?
I was thinking about
about Jessica,
her last minutes.
how she probably couldn't understand why this was happening to her.
what was going through her mind
when his hands were around her throat.
What was
when he was inside of her.
She was only seven.
Do you want to marry her or not?
Of course I want to marry her.
Then act like it!
What have I done?
You're done nothing, Bobby.
That's the problem.
She shows you her dress, you hardly glance at it.
The invitations you couldn't be bothered.
You've completely disengaged her. I don't blame her.
All that stuff is so trivial.
It's a big deal to her!
Bobby, this is the biggest day of her life.
That should mean something to you. Does it?
Of course it does.
Then show her that.
We're in May, you got a June wedding,
you haven't even picked out your best man yet.
Look at me!
You're always on the hustle.
Don't let your wedding day sneak up on you.
You're always dashing off to court, trying to get this guy free,
trying to get that guy bail,
trying to overturn what happened to the other guy.
Lindsay's your life.
I know that.
Show her that too.
How many days after your daughter's death
did you see on the news that the police were about to make an arrest?
Three.
And after hearing this news,
you then retrieved your gun?
Yes.
You then called your real estate broker and canceled your appointment?
And you drove to the suspect's house?
Yes.
And you decided to park at a neighbour's house
so you wouldn't be detected by the police?
Yes.
Where did you keep your gun at home, Ms. Berg?
In the safe.
Combination safe?
Yes.
Do you keep it loaded?
No. I have to load it.
Thank you.
Ms. Berg,
I'm deeply sorry for your loss.
You're here to put me in prison, Ms. Gamble.
Don't tell me how sorry you are,
unless you've had a child taken from you,
you can't begin to understand my loss.
Ms. Frutt?
The witness may step down.
Please call your next witness.
The defense rests.
Explain that to me.
I will.
We don't even call an expert?
Sally was our strongest witness,
better to rest on her than doctor dope
who Helen would have cleaned ** like a trout.
We need somebody to say she was insane.
No, we don't.
Yes, we do.
We have an affirmative defense, Eugene.
We have a legal burden to prove it.
Ellenor, our case won't depend on proving Sally Berg is insane.
Everybody in the room knows she wasn't.
We know it, the prosecution knows it.
So does the jury.
Our case is getting those 12 people to want to send her home.
And Sally's testimony is what we need to ring in their ears.
Not doctor Lanning who goes from courthouse to courthouse collecting cashier's checks.
Our defense is emotion.
We rest on the highest note.
I agree.
You're forgeting Judge Hiller,
she is going to instruct.
If our case came down to doctor Lanning, we'd be dead.
He is right, Ellenor.
Temporary insanity, we just arguing that with a wink.
The jury knows it.
If we try to fool them, we just lose credibility.
Eugene is right.
It's a big risk.
But we have to take it.
You ready to close?
Well, I guess I have to be.
That was very moving for me, getting the marriage license.
How was it for you?
Why are we fighting?
We always seem to fight when we talk about getting married.
Why?
I don't know.
Do you want to get married, Bobby?
Lindsay, I would marry you tonight.
I just hate weddings.
And I'd be lying if I said I was getting all excited about this ceremony.
How can a person hate weddings?
Because it's all about the catering and the dresses and the flowers and
who's invited and who's sitting at whose table.
It should be the most intimate moment of a couple's life.
And they spend the day making sure the guests are taken care of.
There's so much pressure that everything go smoothly.
I hate weddings.
There. I said it.
But marriage, I can't wait for that.
Would you really rather elope?
Truthfully, yes.
It would be you and me without all the distractions.
But I know you want the big wedding day.
And if that's your dream.
I wish it were your dream.
Lindsay, I've only had two dreams my whole life.
One was to pitch for the Red Sox,
the other was to meet and marry the greatest woman in the whole world.
One for two isn't bad.
Now, if I could just get you to take a little medication for your mood swings.
Is that so?
Ow, ow, oh, okay, okay. Uncle!
I suppose we could pass a law
If you kill my child, I get to kill you.
If you rape my child, I get to kill you.
On a pure emotional level,
that doesn't really offend me, truth be told.
On an emotional level,
I admit to take some satisfaction in Michael Whittier's death,
if he did what he was accused of.
I say if because I'm not sure yet.
Michael Whittier never got his day in court.
He was executed before proving guilty.
None of us can take any satisfaction in that,
emotionally or intellectually.
One of the reasons we have laws
is to prevent people from going around with guns
being ruled by their emotions.
I sympathize with Sally Berg,
as I know you do.
But she wasn't acting out of insanity on that day.
She made a series of concious choices.
She had the steadiness in her hand to open a combination lock,
to load a revolver,
to drive a car through traffic without incident.
She had the presence of mind to park where she could  avoid police detection.
She had an understanding that what she did was illegal.
That's indicated by her raising her hands in surrender
immediately after firing the shots.
She willfully, deliberately
with malice aforethought,
committed a pre-meditated murder.
I don't think there is any doubt about that.
The only real question here is
whether you'll embrace her vigilantism by becoming vigilantes yourselves,
or you'll instead uphold the law you swore to uphold.
This is your trial now, ladies and gentlemen.
This is your society.
I'm not a psychiatrist,
and neither is Mr. Bay.
But I know of no medical opinions or studies
that say rage automatically makes you act wildly.
Sometimes if the rage is profound enough,
I would've imagine it could take you over,
to a point where you were even capable of cold  methodical vegence.
This is the kind of profound rage,
and grief,
that took over Sally Berg.
I won't pretend to know what was going on inside her head.
I have never had a child raped and murdered.
And I would guess none of us here would presume to know such horror.
This is Jessica Berg.
She loved to collect and trade pokemon cards.
She liked her stuffed animals more than her dolls.
She...
She loved to play soccer.
I would like to take a moment.
And I would ask you to try and imagine
the last few minutes of her life.
Imagine being her mother.
You're going to elope?
Shhh, he'll hear you.
Well, isnt he going to be a part of it?
I'm gonna surprise him.
You're going to throw a surprise elopement?
This is the best way to handle those 390 invitations.
We elope, and tell people we're already married.
Then we have a small ceremony later and invite the people that we really want.
Tonight?
Tonight.
Like in 3 hours from right now?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
If I lose this trial because you cried...
They didn't see me cry.
So you cover your face,
I doubt they'd thought you were trying to hide a pimple.
The problem isn't me crying.
The problem is there were tears in the jurors' eyes.
Look,
Ellenor said she'd still be willing to take involuntary.
I think we should give it to them.
I thought they hate that upstairs.
If she walks, they'll hate that worse.
I'll talk to Scott.
No.
Helen, if we plead out on involuntary,
the perception upstaris would be I lost.
I need a guilty here.
This can't be about job security.
Easy for you. You're not under review.
Richard.
She committed a first degree murder, Helen.
I don't want to give her involuntary.
And I don't want to lose my job.
The judge is gonna keep them until 9:00 since it's Friday.
And if they haven't decided by then,
they're gonna suspend until Monday.
Me too.
Richard said no to involuntary.
Why?
Principle, I guess.
You can overrule him, Helen.
It's his call.
Ellenor, can I talk to you in private for a second?
I just talked to Lindsay.
She and Bobby are getting married tonight.
What?!
She's surprising him with an elopement.
Oh, men just love to be surprised like that.
Are you serious?
Yes. She says she wants us to be there,
I said we could be here until 9.
She's gonna try and hold the service,
but the priest's got a plane to catch.
Is she pregnant?
No. She says this is what he really wants.
She wants to surprise him.
Helen.
Ellenor.
Jury is back.
Thank you.
The defendant will please rise.
Madam Foreperson, the jury has reached a unanimous verdict?
We have, your honor.
What say you?
Commonwealth vs. Sally Berg,
on the count of murder in the first degree,
we find the defendant not guilty.
on the count of murder in the second degree,
we find the defendant guilty.
Members of the jury, this completes your service.
Security, take the defendant into custody.
We're adjourned.
Sally,
we're gonna appeal.
We'll appeal it.
It's a life sentence.
We're gonna do everything that we can.
I promise.
All right. Enough is enough.
What the hell's going on?
Well, this is your bachelor party.
Bachelor party?
Rebecca, guys are supposed to throw bachelor parties.
Yeah, well, we just wanted to make sure you got one.
You know, sometimes weddings can just sneak up on you.
And how sad would it be if you didn't actually get to have, OW!
What happened?
Rebecca just hit me.
Where am I?
All right, all right. Turn around.
Should I give the signal?
No no no, not yet.
What signal?
Okay, take your blindfold off.
Now, Lucy!
What? I'm in Fenway Park?
Yes you are.
But why? What am I doing here?
Well, you're doing what everybody does in Fenway Park.
You're eloping.
Excuse me?
Oh my God. Oh my God.
Is this for real?
If you want it to be.
Hey, Bobby.
You can do this?
I got special permission from the bishop.
And it would be official?
Like Pearl Harbor.
Quiet!
It would be official.
I figured we could have a more traditional ceremony a little later
with families and close friends.
But tonight, I thought you'd like to pitch for the Red Sox.
I'll catch.
I don't mean to rush, but I have a 10:00 flight.
You're not rushing. I want you to do this right.
Are you sure?
Let's get married.
Hold on!
Did we miss it?
You're about to.
Oh, God. I'm gonna cry.
In addition to the flight, I'm getting old! Can we ?
Okay, ready. If you are.
I do. I am.
Look, they're on the scoreboard!
Please.
Father.
Okay.
Now, this is obviously not a cathedral known for its happy endings.
But Fenway park is certainly a symbol
of a deep life-long commitment of joy and of pain.
Father
I, Bobby
Take thee Lindsay
To be my wedded wife. To have and to hold
From this day forward, for better or for worse
From this day forward, for better or for worse,
for richer, for poorer, in sickness and health,
I've been memorizing this for a long time.
To love and to cherish.
Till death do us part. This is my solemn vow.
Well, I, Lindsay
I, Lindsay
Uh, you haven't memorized this, have you?
I need a little help.
All right. Take thee Bobby to be my wedded husband
Take thee Bobby to be my wedded husband
To have and to hold, from this day forward
For better, for worse; for richer, for poorer
In sickness and in health, to love and to cherish
Till death do us part.
Do you have the rings?
Not yet.
Oh. All right.
Then by the power vested in me under the Commonwealth of Massachusetts,
under God, and I suppose under the Boston Red Sox,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
I guess that means he's off the market now.
I love you.
Lindsay: I love you.
Do we all get to go on the honeymoon?
Uh, one toast.
Thank you all for being here.
Probably goes without saying, which is good because I never say it.
But, you people are my best friends.
You mean the world to me.
And this woman , she is my world.
And people shouldn't cry on baseball fields, let's go.