Previous on The Practice:
Can you tell me the crime your son’s been convicted of?
He’s on death row in Pennsylvania.
He’s to be executed in five weeks.
He’s convicted of raping and killing his girlfriend, Alisha Kerns,
then killing her mother.
Any DNA?
They didn’t do full DNA analysis back then.
This is Ellenor Frutt.
Hello.
She says you can do something, can you really?
We are trying to get the DNA test in order to prove that he’s innocent
but we can’t get that test unless we prove that he’s innocent first?
Right.
How the hell can that be?
Can you think of anybody else
who may have wanna harm your daughter or your wife?
They got the real killer, Mr. Berluti.
Your testimony was especially powerful, you said that he confessed to you.
What do you want from me?
A statement saying that you lied, that he never confessed.
You can be sure it was Stuart Donavan you saw going to the house?
It was between 11:30 and 12.
My husband was a drunk back then.
He could’ve believed it was 11:30 when it may have been 9.
Well, we feel the jury in this case,
given all these new information
quite likely would have returned with a verdict of not guilty.
We are not persuaded that
they could not have reasonably returned with the guilty just the same.
The petitioner’s request for a DNA test is therefore denied.
We are adjourned.
You’ve got to be kidding.
This is a matter of life and death.
I am sorry, without an appointment there is really not …
I have been trying to make an appointment.
You offered me one of two days in July,
by that time Stuart Donovan will be dead.
Ms. Frutt, the Governor did consider your request,
and as far as…
I don’t mean to be rude. But I don’t believe he did.
Because from everything I’ve read about him
he is not only intelligent but he is extremely fair minded.
And there is no way he would’ve denied this reprieve
had he considered the facts of…
I assure you he did.
I’d like to hear from him.
Ms. Mathers, I am asking for 30 seconds’ of his time
and after that you can have me escorted out.
How would this administration run, Ms. Frutt,
if we were to give 30 seconds to every attorney
who marched in here looking to stay an execution.
Actually I think it would run just fine.
This is the second execution in four years.
One minutes in four years isn’t likely to cripple his administration.
I am afraid I have to ask you to leave.
Could you give him this note?
I am afraid I can’t, I am sorry.
Could you pass on a gesture?
Your 30 seconds with me are up.
Since 1985, nation wild,
there have been at least 10 botched executions by lethal injection.
Mr. Berluti, what is the basis of this petition?
That to subject my client to lethal injection
would have amount to cruel and unusual punishment
given the likelihood that the…
Counsel, for us to order that DNA test
you have to show that a reasonable jury couldn't have found your client guilty.
We went through all that last week.
We turned you down, what’s changed in the last nine days?
Well, Your Honour, I thought perhaps the court turned us down
mainly on the constitutional grounds.
That’s why we’ve come back today with stronger constitutional grounds
that being the eighth amendment:
cruel and unusual punishment.
The petition is denied and defence counsel is fined a thousand dollars.
We are adjourned.
Wait a second,
we are trying to save an innocent man from being put to death,
and you are fining me now a thousand dollars?
I am, sir.
You’re here with nothing new.
Taking up the time of a District Attorney, three federal judges
not to mention all the court employees.
And the fine is going up to 1500 if you say another word.
Suppose the tubes close like they have in the past,
I am not entitled to be concerned about that?
The court will allow, counsel, to inspect the execution as the equipment.
The fine is now 1500.
听写：诸如
时间轴：美溪客
Okay, great, thank you.
Okay, Lucy, Joe Bullock, prisoner informant,
supposedly Earl Taylor’s mentor,
he told him everything he knows.
I’d like you to go and see if you could find out
how Earl learned the details of crime.
You want me to meet with him?
Evidently he has a thing for young girls.
Forget it.
You will be separated by a partition.
You just have to go and talk to him.
Do I have to?
No.
But you might be our best shot.
The clothes.
Excuse me.
Alisha Kerns was raped and killed while wearing a night shirt.
So?
So there is nothing in here about it ever being tested,
all the semen was came from the rape kit’s swab.
So what?
Well, the rape kit was introduced to trial
that’s why they say it's not new evidence.
The night shirt, that was never introduced,
we can make the argument that would be new evidence.
It was never tested, maybe there is something on it.
Where would the night shirt be?
She probably went to the coroner with it.
We sent it to the mortuary.
The night shirt.
That’s what it says:
the father of the victim requested that we sent it along with the body to the mortuary.
Why the hell would he request that?
Kerns, he must be Jewish.
What?
Yeah.
It’s an ancient Jewish custom,
let the victim of a violent crime be buried in the clothes they died in.
It’s thought to arouse compassion in god and hasten the end of the exile.
Really?
She was buried in the night shirt, it’s in the coffin.
What are you? 15?
If you could help me, sir,
Stuart Donovan is scheduled for execution the day after tomorrow…
Show me a little something before we get started.
I am not gonna flash you.
I am told that you know how Earl Taylor got the details on Stuart Donovan’s case.
Show me one of your tity.
Mr. Bullock, I am here ask…
One little tity will speak volumes.
You give I give, little miss,
that’s the way justice works.
Now you say somebody’s life is at stake.
You tell me what you know and I will decide how much I show you.
Booty upfront, that’s the way it works.
Goodbye, Mr. Bullock.
Wait wait, no no, wait.
Okay.
He got the facts about the murder by calling the coroner’s office
pretending to be a police officer,
it ain’t hard, most are stupid.
He calls an inmate reception centre,
to get the skinny on the purp,
pretending to be a bail bondsman.
Next he calls the DA’s record room,
posing as an asassistant District Attorney.
It’s all you need to find out anything about any crime.
You can get all these on a phone from prison?
Fifteen minutes, I’ve seem Earl do it less.
All right, lady, tity show time.
That’s it? Stomach?
Bye Joe.
What? I give you everything and you give me stomach?
Man…
You want to what?
A court order allowing us to exhume the body of Alisha Kerns.
Your Honour denied our request to have the rape kit tested
because it was old evidence.
The night shirt and the casket is new evidence.
How is that new evidence?
It was no secret Alisha Kerns was wearing a night shirt
on the night of the crime
with due diligence Mr. Donovan’s lawyers could have tracked it down years ago.
It was not foreseeable
that the victim would be buried in the night shirt she died in
in accordance with an ancient Jewish custom.
And with the existence of the rape kit,
there was never a need to go looking for it.
I would submit that we have a right to post conviction discovery.
Under exceptional circumstances.
Stuart Donovan is about to be put to death,
if that is not exceptional circumstances…
You don’t know there is DNA on that night shirt.
If there is not, what are you afraid of?
You still get to execute him
and you don’t have to cancel your party plans.
I direct the court to Commonwealth versus Cleveland,
the court of appeals denied defendant’s motion for exhumation
because the existence of the evidence saw was speculated and uncertain.
Cleveland involved looking for trace of gunpowder residue,
that's nowhere near the scientific certainty of DNA.
Your Honour, this crosses a line.
They are looking to desecrate a grave
and victimize Mr. Kerns yet one more time.
I object to that.
I'd also like to point out that the prosecution of Stuart Donovan
has now cost the taxer payer’s over one million dollars.
They had a trial; they had an appeal;
they have since gone on to the state’s supreme court,
the federal circuit court;
they’ve come back to you twice,
they’ve gone to the United State Supreme Court.
For every one of these Hail Mary’s,
the District Attorney’s office must file brief, we must show up.
We are now going on 13 years for over a million dollars,
now they come in looking to dig up the victim
where in god’s name does it stop?
With one simple DNA test.
All right.
The night shirt may very well be new evidence,
but there is no offer before me
that it even contains any DNA evidence much less exculpatory.
Because nobody looked.
Even so, under Cleveland, I can’t reopen on speculation.
And that’s all you're bargaining with.
Your motion is denied.
We’re still trying.
Lucy got some information on Earl Tylor how he gets his information.
And we are gonna go to Mr. Kerns tomorrow.
He can authorize us to dig up the body.
Why would any father agree to let his daughter get dug up?
It’s over.
Not yet.
Where is my mother? Out crying now?
She’s at home.
I've never believed that would happen.
Even when I got sentenced
I figure, you know, it’s a mistake, I will get cleared up.
Well, there.
The date is here.
Jimmy and Eugene are gonna go look at the equipment.
It’s only been used once in the past four years,
so maybe if they could find…
Why don’t we just go and dig up the body ourselves?
We can’t do that.
Why? Is this a crime?
I’ll serve the time.
If I get DNA to clear my son.
We can’t do that.
Listen, it’s probably not a bad idea
for you to go with Jimmy to see the father,
a mother’s agony.
Does he know you are coming?
He doesn’t know what I am coming to ask him.
And Euegen, I guess you should check the executional equipment, who knows.
You okay?
I am fine.
How did you expect me to respond, Mr. Berluti?
Terrible.
According to the mortician
the night shirt was folded and put in the casket.
We wouldn’t have to touch the remains of your daughter.
I can’t believe I am sitting in my own living room listening…
Mr. Kerns, you and I have never spoken.
We both lost our children…
Mrs. Donovan, you and I have nothing in common.
If there is DNA that matches up with my son,
I will drop any further appeal…
You’re asking me
to dig up my own daughter’s grave.
Mr. Kerns, I would think a father would want to know for sure…
Oh, you would think that, would you, Mr. Berluti?
You won’t get closure unless you are sure.
You put that night shirt in the casket asking for god’s compassion.
The compassion we are asking for is yours.
Please. I am begging you.
What would you do?
Just open the lid, take the night shirt
and put her right back in the ground.
All set?
Ready.
Connects to the execution.
On the count of three.
One, two, three.
Done.
Okay, let’s start from the top.
This time we will do it as if the condemned was struggling.
Yes, I understand that you’ll get back to me,
but I just want it brought to Justice Stroud’s attention
that the execution date is tomorrow.
Yes.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Supreme Court Justices aren’t even made aware of these request.
Their law clerks just stamp denied
and then they go out to play basketball.
Hello.
One second, please.
It’s the doctor from the lab.
Doctor Donum, Ellenor Frutt.
Are you sure?
Okay, thank you.
Let me discuss it here and I will call you back.
Thank you.
Well?
There was DNA on the night shirt.
Two semen stains.
It did not match Stuart’s.
Thank you, god. Thank you.
And we can document chain of custody.
Doctor Donum is a DNA specialist that your office uses
so you certainly aware of his credentials.
Wow…
I am hoping we can now offer a joined recommendation
asking for Stuart Donovan’s release.
Well, I am not sure I can do that.
Well you now have conclusive prove he didn’t do it.
Did doctor Donum put these into the national database?
He did, there’s been no ID.
Look, I am not gonna pretend I am not shocked here
obviously this comes as quite a surprise.
But it doesn’t clear Stuart Donovan.
It only means somebody else could have been there with him that night.
What?
Stuart Donovan was seen going into that house.
At 9 o’clock.
No. The witness said between 11:30 and 12.
The witness was a drunk who saw Johnny Carson on TV
and thought it was between 11:30 and 12.
Mr. Young, we didn’t convict with semen stains on the night shirt,
we convicted with eye witness’s testimony,
we convicted with his confession.
The confession was a lie.
You say so, but I don’t have any evidence of that.
I don’t believe I am hearing this,
you still plan to execute?
This new evidence only goes to show
somebody else could have been there in addition to your client.
Or it could have been an old stain from the day before, the week before.
It doesn’t disprove the evidence against Stuart Donovan.
How could they not let him go now?
I don’t understand.
Come on, back to court.
Federal?
Common, please.
Judge Wood?
If we went to Federal, they'd kick us back to State court on this.
But state definitely don’t want to see me again.
Judge Wood.
He’s all we got.
Lucy, let’s go.
We can’t go to federal?
Jimmy, see if there is a State court Law that we…
Why Judge Wood?
Would you shut up!
I am sorry.
It’s just…
I am so sorry.
Lucy, we need an affidavit of what Joe Bullock told you.
Jimmy, get a declaration of Doctor Donum plus test results.
Done.
And keep calling the Supreme Court, harass them.
You want me to argue?
No. I will do it.
Mary.
It’s okay.
Conspiracy?
Now they think it’s conspiracy?
We’re going in to court again in the morning.
Why are they doing this?
Because they are desperate to believe they’ve got the right guy.
Look, we've arranged to have you transfer to the court.
Your presence there could count for something.
Have we heard from the Supreme Court?
They don’t seem to be returning our calls this week.
Where is Ellenor?
She’s working on her statement for tomorrow’s hearing.
We are not giving up, honey.
Listen, if we lose
they will be taking you directly from court to the…
the place.
The place
you mean the place where they put me to death?
If you get people to say goodbye to here,
you’ll have to do it in the morning.
Whose semen was it?
We don’t know.
I don’t think it proves anything, Michael.
There could have been co-conspirators.
And they are going back into the court again?
Before Judge Wood.
These lawyers… they don’t quit.
They dug up the rape kit on their own.
They… they are very good, Michael.
I’ll argue.
Really?
This is the killer, right?
I know it is.
I’ll argue.
We are not losing him on the day of execution.
Hey.
How is it going?
Okay, I’ve just…
I’ve got so much here, I just…
I am not sure how to organize it all, you know,
or even if I should argue everything.
Judge Wood, he looks like…
I just don’t know how long he’s gonna pay attention.
When he first went to prison
he kept banging his head up against the bars,
for 48 hours he kept banging.
He said that he wouldn’t stop until somebody heard the truth.
And then they put him on antipsychotic medication for three years.
Three years.
Ellenor, you can’t take these things too personally.
You won’t be any good to him if you let your emotions take over tomorrow.
Maybe you should do it, Eugene.
I am not as ready as you are.
I am having a hard time keep it all assorted.
My anger, what happened to him,
what truth is relevant to this type of hearing,
what’s not…
I can tell you one thing,
I am never gonna do another death penalty case.
I can’t handle it.
I just can’t.
All rise.
Be seated.
All right, Ms. Frutt, here we are again.
The floor is yours.
May I please the court,
we now have conclusive DNA evidence
establishing it was somebody else not Stuart Donovan
who raped Alisha Kerns on that night,
you have the reports in front of you.
You also have the affidavit of Joe Bullock,
outlining exactly how Earl Tylor learned the details of the crime
which details allowed Earl Tylor to go to the District Attorney
with the falsified confession.
A confession he used to get his own prison sentence reduced.
You also have an affidavit from his ex-wife
stating that Mr. Brasler was habitually drunk
and passed out by 9 o’clock every night.
Mr. Brasler claims it was between 11:30 and 12
when he saw my client entered the victim’s house
and he’s basing that on the fact
that Johnny Carson was on the television.
We have also shown by affidavit
that Johnny Carson was in fact on during prime time the night of the murders
9 p.m. to 11 p.m.
in an anniversary special.
My client was convicted on three pieces of evidence, Your Honour.
A confession fabricated by a jail house snitch.
The eye witness testimony of an alcoholic
who was confused as to what time it really was.
And a blood type match
which is now been conclusively disproven with DNA testing.
As a matter of law, as a matter of simple justice,
Stuart Donovan’s conviction must be set aside
and he must be released immediately.
Mr. Stanfield?
We will not deny to this court we were shocked by the DNA evidence.
We then test the rape kit and learned just 10 seconds ago
it too did not match to Donovan.
My first reaction yesterday to the DNA discovery was that
Stuart Donovan should in fact be set free.
But when we stop to think about it,
nothing has changed so dramatically that it will alter the verdict.
As Ms. Frutt correctly states
Stuart Donovan was convicted on three pieces of evidence.
First, the confession,
that confession still stands.
It was introduced into evidence at trial and challenged at trial.
Defence isn’t free to continue challenging it
after the verdict without new evidence.
And they don’t have any.
They can argue all they want that is fabricated
that argument was made at trial and rejected by the jury.
Second, the eyewitness’s testimony.
Again, the defence argued at trial that Mr. Brasal must've been mistaken
but there is nothing else to controvert that eyewitness’s testimony.
Just as there is nothing else to controvert it today.
Third, the blood match.
If you look at the court transcripts
this was never a big part of the prosecution’s case.
If you review the closing arguments
you will see we hammered two points:
The confession and the eyewitness’s testimony.
Now, we can all say I would never agree with the jury on those points
but that is not the standard for a review.
The question you have to ask
is whether these new evidence is of such character
that a different verdict will likely result.
The answer to that is no.
Because there is nothing to disprove either the confession or that testimony.
Not then, not now.
All right, I will grant you that, Mr. Stanfield.
The court has no basis to throw out the confession
or the eyewitness’s testimony.
But this new DNA evidence
doesn’t that tell us somebody else did it?
No, Your Honour.
It tells us that somebody else could have been there;
somebody else made love to her.
We have no timeline on that, could have been earlier.
But it doesn’t change the fundamentals of our case.
And let’s remember this
Mr. Donovan didn’t confessed to Mr. Tylor
that he raped anybody or that he made love to the victim before killing her.
He confessed only to murdering the two women.
Hence, this new evidence does nothing
to undermine the veracity of that confession.
Do you still think he did it?
My personal beliefs aren't relevant.
There are relevant to me.
Do you think this is the man who killed those women?
I do, your Honour.
He had a heated fight with Alisha Kerns just the day before.
He refused to accept the end of the relationship.
There is no sign of forced entry, so the idea of home invasion.
No fingerprints but his, no motive for anybody else.
Look, he confessed to the crime.
You don’t free a man just because
it turns out that somebody else may have been there at the time.
But you have to admit
it does change things if somebody else was there.
Not enough to upset a verdict.
Recently the Texas Court of Appeals was faced with the exact situation.
The DNA turned out not to match the defendant.
The court refused to grant a new trial
ruling that the DNA results did not preclude the presence of a co-conspirator.
That was the case there, it's what we have here.
You have precedent.
You have the verdict of a jury.
This court should honour both.
You can’t rest. He was good.
One more minute, Your Honour.
Go ahead.
Five weeks ago when I took this case,
I almost immediately started getting emotional about it.
And I couldn’t figure out why.
I don’t know Stuart Donovan.
I realize now that what got to me is the reality
that people don’t get fair trials in this country, they often don’t.
Mr. Frutt, I was the Judge on your client’s trial.
And I don’t doubt that you did everything right, Your Honour.
But Stuart Donovan had a public defender
who had just finished another capital case
48 hours before his trial began.
And that public defender wasn’t ready for this one.
He didn’t discover a lot of the things he could have.
Defence lawyers, especially public defenders,
especially those taking court appointments,
we just don’t have enough time,
we just don’t have the resources.
And it’s… it’s understandable.
Things are bound to fall to the cracks, how could they not?
But I have a man facing death here.
Technically, from an evidentially standpoint,
Mr. Stanfield is right, the confession still stands.
the eyewitness’s testimony is valid,
the time to impeach it would have been at trial,
that never happened.
Technically, the prosecution’s two big pieces of evidence still hold up.
Technically.
In reality, a man is going to be executed for a crime he didn’t commit.
And as I have been pounding my head against walls,
I had been continuingly hearing:
Mr. Frutt, there is a system,
a system of evidence and appeals and…
They system doesn’t always work, Your Honour.
In the last ten years alone,
over 44 people have been released from death row
from crimes they didn’t commit.
The system uses jail house snitches who fabricate confessions;
the system has police lying;
the system is very, very fallible.
And maybe it’s understandable,
given the enormous volume of criminal cases today,
mistakes happen, lies happen.
It is a byproduct of the system that I can almost comprehend.
But what I can’t fathom
is that when we have the ability
to find out the truth through DNA evidence,
we don’t.
In 48 states, this being one of them,
prisoners do not have the right to a simple DNA test
that can prove their innocence.
You wouldn’t let us have one, Judge.
We had to go to the father of the victim,
miraculously he let us dig up his daughter.
And after we did that, did the test on our own,
we pretty much proved Stuart Donovan’s innocence.
And still it hasn’t ended.
Mr. Stanfield now gets up, changes the prosecution's theory
and refocuses the court’s attentions on eyewitness’s testimony
and a jail house informant
which everyone in the room regards a suspect.
As technically admissible as it may be on evidently grounds,
none of us in this room fully believe that snitch,
none of us fully trust that eyewitness' account
and a man is going to die.
Is our system about getting convictions?
Is that it?
My co-counsel, Eugene Young,
told me not to take this case personally.
How can I not?
How can't we all?
A man,
an innocent man is going to die.
As human beings,
as officers of this court,
as players in this system,
how do we not take that personally?
I hear Ms. Frutt’s frustration or emotion;
I’d like the court to consider it from our side
and from the victim’s families.
You find the person who commits the murder,
you put that person on trial, you secure a conviction.
That’s not easy these days,
but even when you're lucky enough to get that far,
the defence attorneys keep coming back over and over and over again
raising constitutional claims
saying that the previous attorneys weren’t good enough.
Twelve years they have been coming back on this one,
twelve years this father, this husband
has been waiting for this to be over.
And this on the case where the defendant confessed,
this on the case where we have eyewitness' testimony.
Most times, the defence attorneys are in here
trying to free their clients on technical grounds,
Exulting the system above all else.
But here where the system has been adhere to,
where the evidence is all sound technically,
they’re in here…
We have his confession on record,
the jury believed that confession.
Why don’t we just let everybody go?
I am persuaded by defence counsel’s arguments
that before we put a man to death
we should be sure of the person’s guilt
and not simply limit our inquiry
as to whether the trial was technically sound
from an evidentiary stand point.
That seems so obvious.
But Mr. Stanfield’s contention is also a valid one.
We could keep reevaluating evidence ** forever.
The point of a trial is to reach a final verdict on the facts,
and though it would be nice to reconsider the confession,
take a second or third look at the testimony,
if we did that for one, we'd have to do it for all.
And if we did it for all
surly the court docket would clot beyond repair
and it would be no justice to anybody.
Ms. Frutt, it was the confession and the eye witness’s testimony
that convicted your client.
Both of these elements were vigorously challenged at trial
and though you clearly like to keep on renewing the challenge
under the law you don’t get to,
not with what you brought me.
But Mr. Stanfield,
had you had this DNA evidence
clearly you would have been investigate the possibility of another suspect,
you didn’t.
I am an old man.
I look at each cigarette as possibly my last.
My last breath won’t be spent executing a man
I now think is probably innocent.
The conviction is set aside,
Mr. Donovan, you are free with the apologies of this court.
Adjourned.
How about that?
Yeah!