When did this happen?
Eight days ago.
Why didn’t the hospital notify the police?
Admitting says he wasn’t convinced the crime had been committed.
I don’t believe him.
He also says he wanted her to heal first
before asking any tough questions.
That maybe true.
She’s been read her rights?
Twice.
She didn’t ask for a lawyer?
She hadn't said anything, she won’t talk.
Hi, Jenny,
my name is Helen Gamble.
I am a District Attorney.
I know you're scared,
being brought in by the police, you must be terrified.
I am not the police, okay?
And I think I can help you,
But you're gonna have to trust me first.
I...I just wanna leave.
And I will make sure you do.
But first, I…
I just want you to tell me what happened, okay?
Now, Doctor Mathew said you tried to kill yourself,
is that true?
Can you tell me why?
Because…
I know this stuff is hard to talk about.
So I’ll tell you what,
I’ll tell you what I do know,
and you can fill in some of the blanks, all right?
You mom threw you out of the house.
When did she throw you out, Jenny?
The day before.
The day before you tried to take your life?
Yes.
Did she throw you out because
she was angry that you were pregnant?
Yes.
And you were seven months?
Why was she so upset, do you know?
She’s always saying
don’t go and get knocked up.
It’s a big thing with her.
So when she found out, she kind of went berserk and stuff,
told me my life would be ruined and…
I don’t know.
What about your dad?
I don’t have a dad.
My mother doesn’t even know who he is or was.
I think that’s…
she got knocked up.
I was probably the baby that ruined her life.
You being pregnant, that’s sort of a huge disaster, uh?
Were you upset when she threw you out of the house?
Yes.
Is that the reason you try to kill yourself?
Probably.
Are you really gonna help me?
You have my word.
I saw that after you stabbed yourself,
I see you then got yourself to a hospital.
Did you then decide you really wanted to live?
Yeah.
It was hurting so bad, I just wanted the pain to go away.
Did you really think you would kill yourself
by stabbing yourself in the stomach, Jenny?
I don’t know.
When I was 19, I got pregnant.
I had an abortion.
I was way too young for a baby.
What are you? 15?
Look, kid, it’s okay.
You need to talk about this,
you can’t try to bury this alone.
Trust me.
I tried to keep everything inside
and it caused me more pain than anything else in my whole life.
It’s okay to talk about it, Jenny.
When you stabbed yourself,
you were only tring to kill the baby, weren’t you?
It’s okay, Jenny.
You are only 15 years old, for…
You just tried to raise a child
and your mom had thrown you out of the house.
You were only tring to kill the baby, isn’t that right?
You thought that if…
if you could make the baby go away, things would be better.
It’s okay, sweet heart.
I am gonna help you.
But first, I am gonna sent someone in
to write down the things we talked about.
Then I am gonna help you get out.
I promise.
Get her a statement.
听写：诸如
时间轴：美溪客
This is the first trial of this kind
where a woman is actually being charged
with fornicating her husband to dead.
Gee, she is in every channel.
…she is now accused of inducing his heart attack with sexual intercourse.
The defence firm of Donnnel Young Dole $ Frutt…
Hey, I gotta run down to the court house,
favor for Helen, some homicide case.
Helen asks a favor on a homicide case?
I’ll call you when I know more.
However, in one of the more amusing polls,
33% of the men said they would nevertheless
still want to have sex with the Black Widow
fully knowing she might then try to kill them.
I would.
32622, Commonwealth versus Jenifer Holbrook,
murder in the first degree.
Ellenor Frutt for the defendant, waive reading,
we enter a plea of not guilty.
Helen Gamble for the Commonwealth,
You Honour, I’d like to conference,
I think we can depose of it today.
A first degree murder case?
I’d like to conference.
Let’s go.
Jenny, I am Ellenor Frutt, I am your attorney here.
And right now I am gonna go back there
and I'm gonna talk to the Judge and the District Attorney
and then I am gonna come back and talk to you, okay?
Okay.
Ok, it’s very important that
you don’t talk to anybody about this, nobody.
All right. I’ll be back in a few minutes.
It’s a prior bad act, inadmissible on the…
It goes to pattern, Your Honour.
She killed her last husband; she killed this one.
She killed neither, and two cannot make a pattern any way.
She could have killed her first husband as well,
that would make three.
Her first husband died of cancer, what are you saying?
She’s clever.
Settle down. I’ll remove you all if I have to.
Your Honour, my client was never charged
-with the murder of her previous husband -She was and still is a suspect
to allow the prosecution to argue this.
Three marriages; three dead husbands.
That’s a pattern.
I am going to allow it.
Appealed.
So noted.Anything else?
No, Your Honour.
Is the Commonwealth ready for trial?
Ready, Your Honour.
Mr. Donnell?
Ready.
Tow o’clock, till then.
I am not sure that was your ** try.
Just preserving the objection for appeal.
The truth is I want them to introduce this stuff.
Why?
Because it’s been on the papers for months,
there is no way those jurors haven’t heard of it.
We’ll need to address it accordingly.
They’re not calling you black widow because you like bugs.
She was thrown out of the house by her mother,
she never had a father; she is 15 years old.
I…I just like to do this quietly
before it become the front page
of the Metro Session which it would be.
What’s your offer?
I’ll give you involuntary manslaughter, three years.
That way she is out when she’s 18 instead of 21.
She might have a shattered life.
Well, I need to look at her file, I'll talk it over with her.
But that sounds great.
Ms. Gamble said she’d help me.
She is, Jenny, trust me.
Involuntary manslaughter is a very good offer
considering this happened in you third trimester.
You could be out by the time you are 18.
And even if we went to trial and won on diminished capacity,
you are still looking at as much time.
So I should plead guilty?
Well, first I want you to undergo a psychiatric exam.
Then I'd like to review your statement
in the police report a little more, but…
yes, it’s an excellent deal
and I think we should jump at it.
Has your mom come to see you yet?
I don’t think she even knows.
Could you tell her?
Sure.
I am gonna get Lucy Hatcher, my assistant
to come in and talk to you.
We are gonna need to get you some new clothes for court, okay?
All right.
I am gonna be in touch.
And were you able to determine the cause of death, Doctor?
Acute cardiac arrest.
You did toxicology tests?
We did.
Anything remarkable on those tests?
We found traces of the drug commonly known as Viagra.
I never ever prescript Viagra for Jerry.
Did you ever talk about Viagra with him?
Yes, we did.
And I told him on no uncertain terms
taking that drug would be a death sentence.
Why is that, doctor?
Jerry had a weak heart.
He'd gone through two separate by pass operations.
The very last thing he should had been taken
is a pill to facilitate sexual marathons.
The reason you were talking about Viagra with Jerry Hanson
is because he wanted it,
isn’t that right, doctor?
-Yes, but I…  -Thank you.
And in addition to being jerry Hanson’s doctor,
were you also his friend?
Yes, I was.
His death was very upsetting for you?
Do they teach that in law school?
It's upsetting when friends die?
Doctor.
Of course I am upset.
And if you believe my client was responsible for his death,
you wanna see her convicted, wouldn’t you?
Objection!
Goes to bias.
You’ve made the point, move on.
Doctor, you said Jerry wanted to perform better with my client.
Yes.
Sexually perform?
Yes, sexually perform.
She wanted him to perform better and he wanted to perform better.
She played these mind games with him, made him feel inadequate.
Well, if he were feeling inadequate,
could that be why he wanted the Viagra?
Possibly.But I…
And you wouldn’t give it to him.
You made no room for the possibility,
that he might go get it someplace else.
Well, why was it ground up and put into wine?
Move to strike.
If he want to take it…
-She laced the wine and killed him.  -Move to strike.
That’s enough.
Doctor, did you advised Jerry Hanson
to refrain from sexual intercourse altogether?
No, I told him to be very careful and take it slow.
Oh then, why couldn’t he take the drug
just to help him perform but carefully and slowly?
People with heart conditions do use this drug sometimes,
isn’t it right, doctor?
Yes, but I didn’t think it was indicated for Jerry.
Why not?
Because knowing Jerry, I was afraid he would try to keep up with her.
And add Viagra, his heart might give out before…
And knowing Jerry’s nature, he wouldn't have the sense to stop,
was that your fear?
Yes.
Thank you, doctor.
Ms. Holbrook?
Yeah.
My name is Ellenor Frutt, I am an attorney.
What do you want?
I am afraid I have some bad news.
She dead?
Who?
Jenny.
Oh, no, no no no, she’s not dead.
But her baby is, and she has been charged with its death.
She’s in custody now and I am representing her.
What’s gonna happen to her?
Well, she may have to go to a juvenile detention centre until she’s 18,
that’s what we are hoping for.
Three years, a baby lasts a lot longer than that,
she made out good.
Yeah.
We tested the wine,
the results indicated there were remnants of Viagra in it.
And what, if any, conclusions did you draw from this, detective?
That the Viagra had been grounded up and put into the wine.
Her previous husband, Mr. Carter, died of an insulin overdoes.
Accidental?
There was evidence of the report that he was killed by the defendant,
who was still married to him at the time.
What evidence?
He was a diabetic, he gave himself insulin injections daily
and had been for years without incident.
And here we had a massive overdose.
It was hard for us to believe
that he could have made such a huge mistake.
Laden fingerprints on the syringe match the defendant.
She inherited under the will which gave financial motive.
You never charged Mrs. Hansen with Mr. Carter’s death.
No, we were never able to collect enough evidence.
In fact, the truth is you had no evidence,
other than your suspicion, isn’t that right, Detective?
Her prints were on the syringe.
She could have handed him the syringe like she said, possible?
Possible.
We are missing something.
Why?
Their case is lousy.
It’s all circumstantial and innuendo,
Marcia Scott is a smart DA.
and she hasn’t put anything on the table.
We are missing something.
Courtney,
are we?
No. I mean…
What’s his son gonna say?
Just what we talked about.
But he’s had an agenda from the beginning;
he never even wanted me to marry his father in the first place.
Why?
He was afraid I’d kill him.
Because of all the suspicion around my previous husbands’ death.
Well, they must think he as some kind of witness
because they’re resting on his testimony.
We’re missing something.
They could rest by midday tomorrow, so,
let’s go over your testimony.
I go first?
You’re first and last, you’re all we have.
How did it go?
All right.
Did you tell her mother?
Yeah. You know what she said?
Three years, not too bad,
a baby last longer than three years.
Ellenor, Helen told her she could leave.
She also told Jenny about her own abortion
and how she needed to talk about it.
I think she was tricked into that confession.
She told you she had an abortion?
Yes.
And what else?
Just so hard it was for her
and how she made it worse by keeping it all inside.
She said it would be better for me to tell her
and that if I did, she’d make sure I could leave jail.
What else?
She just kept saying how you know,
she understood how I would want to make the baby go away,
and how my life…
I thought she’d help me.
She never said I would be convicted of murder,
she never said that.
My first husband? How was he relevant?
Well, we have to cover the old thing.
All your husbands were years older,
it’s a question the jury will be asking and I'd like to answer it.
It’s not something I really want to get into on the witness stand
in front of a roomful of reporters.
Well, get into it now,
I’ll decide whether it's useful or not.
I…er…
began to develop when I was 11.
My older brother’s friends were copping feels
by the time when I was 12.
When I was 15 college guys were hitting on me.
Even now, your colleague, Mr. Berluti,
and even you…
have your thoughts.
Me? Wh..wh..what have I done?
It’s beside the point.
The point is
I’ve been on my guard with men my whole life.
The only man I ever felt safe with growing up was my dad.
So, I suppose on some level,
my attraction to older men is more about
I’ve been drown to the safety of…
I don’t know.
I...I hope that you don’t feel that I’ve been…
You’ve been nothing but totally professional.
But I know when a man is attracted to me,
sometimes is even before he does.
Ellenor, you didn’t tell her?
I don’t wanna her prepared.
32622, Commonwealth versus Jenifer Holbrook,
Murder in the first degree.
Your Honour, both parties offer joint recommendation
as we discussed in conference.
I am sure Ms. Holbrook…
Actually, Your Honour, defence rescinds such agreement on the plea,
and instead brings a motion to suppress Ms. Holbrook’s confession.
Ellenor.
On what grounds?
My client’s statement was a result of coercion
and was also obtained by violation of Fifth Amendment Rights.
What are you talking about?
Miranda, my client didn’t understand...
She was read her rights twice.
And then she was basically unread them, Helen.
What?
What’s going on here?
Ms. Gamble told my client that if she gave her a statement
she would get to leave.
Basically, Your Honour,
where Miranda says anything you say maybe used against you,
Ms. Gamble told her anything you say maybe used to help you.
Ms. Holbrook is 15 years old,
still in the thrills of a pretty big emotional wallop,
and she believed the promises Ms. Gamble made.
Oh, come on.
Have you ever had an abortion?
She talked to my client about her very own abortion,
in order to get Jenny to admit that she killed her unborn child.
The only thing that matters for the purpose of a confession
is was the suspect read her rights
and did she make the statement voluntarily.
She was, she did.
And I contend she was confused in respect to her right,
deliberately confused and that the statement was not voluntary.
All right.
I would like to see Ms. Holbrook in chambers please.
Excuse me?
You have a problem with me asking a few questions, Counsel?
Nice ambush, Ellenor.
You know, don’t talk to me about ambush, Helen, you used me.
I did no such thing.
You figured I’d be less inclined to doubt your motives,
I don’t like it.
My motive was to help that girl.
And what was it when you went into that room to interrogate her?
To get her statement. Having got a confession
I did have compassion for her.
That is why I came to you.
I don’t know how in good conscious you could trick a 15-year-old…
Your client is a murderer, Ellenor.
You are angry, I understand.
But don’t appeal to me on conscious.
I was suspicious of her from the very beginning.
Why was that?
My father was in his 70’s, frail.
He wasn’t what anybody would call attractive,
nor was he at all charming.
And she falls in love with him?
Did your father ever talk to you
about his relationship with the defendant?
Sometimes.
Specifically, what did he talk about?
Specifically, sex.
He said she was insatiable.
He once said…
Objection, hearsay.
Did he ever seem upset when he spoke of sex?
Once he was excited, yes.
What did he say then?
Objection!
Excited utterance, exception of the hearsay rule.
And he just happened to use that word “excited”?
This witness has been coached.
I object to that.
All right.
Mr. Donnell, your objection is overruled. Please sit.
The witness may answer the question.
What did your father tell you, Mr. Hansen?
He said she would make love so physically sometimes,
it was violent, almost sadistic.
He wondered whether she was trying to give him a heart attack.
What else, sir?
He said she taunted him during sex,
taunted him to go harder, like some weird psychological punishment.
I have nothing further, Your Honour.
Did she say I am going to put Viagra in his wine
and then make love to him till he suffers a coronary,
coz that would be good testimony, Mr. Hansen.
Maybe you should have her say that.
Objection!
Withdrawn.
Did your father feel his life was in danger?
Well, I think a little he did.
Did you take him seriously?
Yes.
Did you notify the police, talk to my client, express your concern?
No.
So you weren’t concerned.
You took the danger seriously, but it didn’t concern you?
What was I supposed to do?
Go to the police and say:
Hey, I think my step-mother is trying to intercourse my farther to death?
If you were concerned, yes.
Tell me, Mr. Hansen,
If my client is convicted of murder,
and becomes disqualifid from the inheritence
who then takes under the will?
That would be me.
That would be you.
Do you think I am sitting in this chair today because of money?
That’s exactly what I think.
I think you are a liar,
Objection.
I think your testimony was false, calculated.
Objection!
Are you lying to get your father’s money?
Counsel.
It’s just a little too damn convenient for me, I am sorry.
My client is being charged with murder for inducing a heart attack,
and you get up here and say:
Gee, my farther told me he was afraid she’d give him a heart attack
when you never said that to anybody before, Mr. Hansen.
And you remember to add he was excited when he said it
to get around the hearsay rule,
well, probably at the District Attorney’s coaching.
Objection!
It’s just a little too convenient.
He’s badgering.
Damn right I am; I badger liars.
Mr. Young, that’s enough.
You said she makes love in a violent way.
That’s what he said, she…
What’s violent to a 70-year-old man?
I don’t know.
Well, did you ask?
Your father says violent,
you don’t follow that up and say:
Dad, what do you mean?
I wish I had.
You said she taunts, she’s sadistic,
she psychologically punishes him,
and you don’t even go to her and say what’s going on?
What kind of caring son are you?
Maybe I should have done…
-Do you know what perjuries is, Craig?  -Objection!
You are under oath here.
Mr. Young.
I am done.
And since, you know, she was an attorney,
I thought…
I thought she would make it so I could leave.
But when you signed this statement?
She said that if I told them exactly what happened
it would be better for me by not keeping stuff inside,
and I…
She told you she had an abortion?
Yes.
And how terrible it was for her
that she kept stuff buried inside and…
You lied to me.
I trusted you and you lied to me.
All right, Jenny,
the detectives told you, did they not,
that the things you said cold be used against you in a court of law.
Yes.
But then she came in and she is an attorney,
and she said they wouldn’t be.
Jenny, I think I'd like you to wait outside for a minute.
Keep her here please.
Aren’t we resourceful?
None of her civil rights were violated.
Did you have an abortion?
No. Tricks are used in interrogations all the time.
This was a lie.
Lies too.
There is nothing unconstitutional about lying to a suspect
so long as they understand their rights,
which she did.
I disagree with that, she didn’t understand her rights.
Oh, come on,
look, we can all try to get inside this girl’s head
but that’s not the way it goes.
We have constitutional dos and don’ts,
we didn’t commit any of the don’ts.
The statement is valid and admissible.
That’s my decision.
I am going to think about it.
We'll reconvene at 2 o’clock.
May I say something?
You’re all thinking about Jenny Holbrook.
I wasn’t called in to talk to Jenny Holbrook.
I was brought down to question a murder suspect,
a suspect who killed a baby,
a suspect who wouldn't talk to the police.
Now, the morality of how I tricked her has no relevance.
This isn’t a moral arena, it is a legal one.
And everything I did was legal,
and she has this back story,
and a fragile personality, and abusive mother,
it all seems just so awful now.
Here’s a flash, killers don’t like to talk.
It’s not easy getting these confessions.
Tag a bunch of moral strings now on top of the constitutional ones,
we will never get anybody.
He brought the Viagra.
Your husband did?
Yes.
Did he say where he'd gotten it?
No.
And then you put it in the wine?
Yes.
He had 50 milligrams one pill and
well, we were talking about the fact that it was now been reported
that women got benefits from taking it too, so
more for a laugh than anything else, we ground up the pill,
and we sprinkled it into our wine.
And then?
After dinner, we watched some television then we went to bed,
and we made love.
And the effects of the Viagra?
Well, it definitely works.
And at some point?
Jerry gripped his chest.
He was having a heart attack.
I called 911 before I am CPR,
but by the time the paramedics got there,
he was gone.
There’s been testimony that you were extremely physical,
and that you taunted…
That’s completely false. Craig Hansen was lying,
his father never said those things to him.
Our love making was never very physical,
it was certainly not violent.
My husband had a heart condition and we were always mindful of it,
both of us.
You say your husband brought the Viagra?
That’s right.
Did you ever get Viagra from your Doctor?
No.
Ever talked to her about the virtues of Viagra for women?
Well, yes, we had discussed that.
Okay. I have nothing further, Your Honour.
Counsel.
The witness may step down.
Mr. Donnell.
The defence rest, Your Honour.
The Commonwealth calsl one rebuttal witness, Doctor Gail Parrent.
Who is she?
She’s my doctor.
Defence object, Your Honour, side bar.
This is my client’s own doctor.
What’s your offer of prove?
She’s prepared to testify she gave the defendant Viagra samples
two days before Jerry Hansen died.
-It’s privileged doctor-patient relationship. -She waived privilege, she opened the door.
How?
During her testimony, she had the right to assert privilege,
she didn’t, she talked about her doctor when I asked…
That is so bogus.
You can’t selectively assert privilege, Your Honour,
the woman did answer questions about things
she discussed with her physician.
I am going to allow it.
You gotta be kidding me.
She opened the door.
I knew we’ve missing something. That was the ace.
You got the Viagra from your own doctor?
I was afraid of how it would look if…
People would think that I secretly put it in his wine.
Did you?
No, it happened exactly as I said.
It didn’t happen as you said.
You got the Viagra and now they caught you in a lie.
Our whole case was your testimony, your credibility,
and now it's shut
Don’t yell at me.
You lied to us, Courtney.
I didn’t kill him, we were making love, I didn’t kill him.
Well, that’s how it looks.
After your doctor testifies,
you have to get back up there and explain to the jury why you lied.
And I hope you're good.
I was just so afraid of how it would look.
Everybody thinks that I killed my last husband,
I was afraid if they knew that I was the one who procured the Viagra…
So you lied.
Yes.
But we both agreed to put it into the wine.
Courtney, why should the jury believe you now?
I don’t have an answer to that, I am…
Why should anybody believe that I could fall in love with an older man?
But I did.
I did.
Let’s talk about that.
You’ve fallen in love three older men.
For whatever reason, I found safety in older men.
They are not as predatory I suppose.
I was telling Mr. Donnell that it probably goes to the safety
that I found with my own father.
You felt safe with your dad?
Your dad died serving time in Carderit prison in New jersey, didn’t he?
He was convicted of raping you when you were nine years old.
He was wrongly convicted.
It never happened.
Your mother and your sister walked in on it, Mrs. Hansen?
Your Honour, could I have time to confer with my client?
No, you may not.
You don’t find safety with these older men, do you, Mrs. Hansen?
You find your anger, your hatred.
He was wrongly convicted,
it never happened.
So, Courtney, any other surprises?
Never happened.
Be seated.
Well, Ms. Gamble, you are completely right,
there is nothing illegal or unconstitutional
about deceiving suspects into giving statements,
it’s been done all the time.
But still, I can’t help but think
that somehow we’ve lost our way.
The whole point of our constitutional safeguard
is to protect the suspect against police misconduct.
Maybe you’re on the letter of the law here,
but the spirit of it took a beating.
Defence counsel’s argument that
the Miranda suspect was in affect de-Mirandazed
it's a valid one.
She is 15.
By the time you got through with her,
she believed she'd help herself by talking,
it doesn’t make sense that
you could read somebody her rights so she'll understand
only then to deliberately confuse her
and smile with a constitutional wink.
It would seem that the player in our system
should at least act in good faith.
But as a judge, I'm bound by precedent
and trickery still survives any constitutional challenge.
I suppose Mr. Gamble said it best,
this is a legal arena, not a moral one.
The statement is allowed.
We’ll conference next Tuesday at 9:00 to set a trial date.
Adjourned.
There's certainly been some surprises here today,
and watching Courtney Hansen on the stand…
Maybe she's got some denial issues
about what happened to her as a child,
maybe it didn’t really happen.
Obviously the prosecution wants you to believe
that she’s acting out of her anger
against these older men she married.
It’s a theory.
But at the end of the day, that’s all they have,
suspicion, jealousy,
innuendo, theory.
There is no evidence to establish that
she purposely caused Jerry Hansen to have a heart attack.
Suspicion? Yes.
But evidence?
What is it?
Jerry Hansen told his son
he was afraid the way she pushed him during intercourse.
And yes, we can consider the way her previous husbands died
because it’s a pattern.
Rich old men, death,
she inherits.
If his father said he felt danger
why did this loving son do nothing?
If she gets convicted, he inherits everything.
Why is this loving son suddenly making noise
as the will goes to probate?
She ground up that Viagra so he wouldn’t detect it, come on.
A man with a weak heart, two by passes,
she has intercourse for over an hour?
If that isn’t reckless disregard,
then what is?
A man with a weak heart prone to pushing too hard has a coronary,
they are charging murder.
That’s out there to begin with,
To prove it, you better have some pretty strong evidence,
they don’t have any.
They are asking you to convict with suspicion.
Why did she lie?
If she’s innocent,
why didn’t she just take that stand and tell us the truth?
But she didn’t do that, did she?
She lied.
Afraid you might get the right idea.
Murder two?
Chance of parole.
If you get convicted of first degree,
you go away forever.
Do you think I'll be convicted?
Strictly on the evidence you shouldn’t be, but...
I am not so sure the jury won’t look beyond the evidence.
The insulin OD of your last husband, that'll hurt.
Your lying on the stand,
that will hurt a lot.
Bobby, I didn’t do it.
26 minutes.
They have a verdict?
What does that mean?
In this case I have no idea.
They could have easily said no evidence or they...
they could have just quickly concluded that you’re guilty,
I have no idea.
Well, if we’re gonna take the deal…
Courtney,
it’s your call.
I will take my chances.
Courtney, the jury is not looking over here,
that’s a bad sign.
If we can still get murder two…
They are not looking over, even one of them.
Still on the table?
Do rush you.
Okay.
Your Honour.
We’ve reached a plea, murder in the second degree.
It’s too late, the jury has returned its verdict.
It’s not too late. The verdict hasn’t been entered.
We are about to enter it, counsel.
It’s not entered. We have a right to reach a plea.
I'll file an interlocutory appeal,
we'll go upstairs and we will argue it.
You really wanna do this?
We’re fine with it. It will spare us an appeal.
I don’t like this last minute stunts, Mr. Donnell.
It’s not a stunt, it’s a legitimate plea agreement.
Mrs. Hansen.
Do you agree to plead guilty to murder in the second degree?
I do, Your Honour.
So entered.
Members of the jury, thank you for your service.
This matter is adjourned.
Sentencing 2 o’clock, Friday.
Mr. Donnell, I am not big on passing notes in class
but you can keep this.
I think we did the right thing.
I will be in, we need…
we need to talk before sentencing.
Okay.
I think we did the right thing.