They turned it down.
So now what?
We either try it, or we up the offer.
I think we could make it go away for 175,000.
175,000 would break me.
I got no coverage for this, Jimmy.
I know.
If we go to trial…
Jury's already sworen in, it would be 2 or 3 days.
It’ll only cost you my time which...
I don’t mean the cost of the trial.
I am asking would we win.
I don’t know, Peter.
Legally, what you did was invasion of privacy.
He has a deadly disease…
And we will certainly argue that.
I’m just telling you I’m not sure we’ll win.
Let’s go to trial.
I ain’t taking murder 2.
Why should I take that?
That’s life. Murder 2.
Why should I take that? That’s life.
I am not necessarily recommending it, Alex.
I’m just making you aware of the state’s offer.
Plus, with murder 2, there is some possibility of parole.
Murder 1…
They will kill me in prison.
I know what happens to people like me.
They will kill me. I know what happens.
You have to beat this, Mr. Young.
Well, I don’t think I will.
The woman you killed…
I didn’t!
Allegedly killed.
She was the daughter of a college chancellor.
She has got a lot of publicity.
And they don’t assign Helen Gamble cases for her charm.
You have to take care of this. I did’t do it.
You have to make them see that. I didn’t do it!
Even so, you have to realize how it looks.
The police discovered you having sex with her.
But she was already dead.
How many times did I have to say it?
So you just found a dead woman in the dumpster,
and decided to have sex with her?
Yes.
And you have to make them see that.
I ain’t going down for murder 2.
All right.
Look, uh, we are gonna have some clothes sent over for you to wear at trial.
We are gonna need you to take a shower.
why?
Because you stink, Mr. Dickson.
You think I’m some kind of animal. That’s what you think.
I am a human being.
听写：夕・夏
时间轴：美溪客
Why not go insanity?
I don’t think he is insane.
Plus, he insists he didn’t kill her.
I assume Helen has got her fangs out.
Oh you have no idea.
Can I ask does Lindsay really need to be on this?
Is that a strategic question or more you don’t want her sit next to the guy?
Probably the latter, I admit.
I’m OK.
It’s a court appointment. We have to give him a defense.
We certainly don’t have to provide two attorneys.
I think having a woman at the table helps.
A radio station gave out our number.
Some DJ’s telling his listeners to call us and tell us we are scum.
Great.
We already knew that.
I’m gonna shut down the phones for the morning.
So let's everybody take their cellulars.
Jimmy, how are you doing?
We have offered 125.000. He turned us down.
Trial starts today.
I’d go higher.
Don’t start.
He revealed the guy’s medical condition.
He didn’t fire the guy. He quit.
After your client set down a memo telling the whole world.
This guy has AIDS, Rebecca. His coworkers…
He also has a right to privacy.
And they have the right to be safe.
All right, enough for the arguing.
125,000 is a line in the sand. We start trial today.
And P.S., I’ve known Peter Hines since high school.
He is not a bigot.
All right. Any second chair?
Thanks. I’ll pass on the chairs here.
-You’re personalizing.  -Let’s go!
Cellulars. Scum today, you guys.
How did Mr. Hines even find out you had AIDS?
We were required to take physicals for our insurance.
He owns the company, somewhere found out I was first diagnosed 3 years ago.
But he didn't tell the other employees at Straub until last year?
Yes, he suddenly decided to circulate an in-office memo
to all employees which totally about 90.
Did he give you an explanation as to why he did this?
Yes. Concern for their health.
And what happened, Mr. Mayfield, after this memo was circulated?
I began to be treated differently.
Some people act like they had to play.
Others, they were wordly hostile.
And I was no longer welcomed to play in our basketball team.
We had an inner office accountant league.
And I was invited to stay at home by our team captain.
So basicly you began to be discriminated against?
Yes. I wasn't totally ostracized, though.
There are some people in the firm with whom I have made friends.
There is even some people who assault me with their sympathy.
They offered me the names of various support groups...
um, I think they are the worst.
I mean there is nothing more oppressive
than a well-meaning sympathize on the lose.
Mr. Mayfield. How was it no longer tolerable to work there?
Well, I went from being an accountant in good standing,
one who enjoyed comradery with my coworkers,
to being the one with AIDS,
the sick one.
But you are the sick one, aren't you, Mr. Mayfield?
I don't prefer to see myself that way.
But you have a fatal disease, don't you?
Yes.
And this disease is infectious, isn't it?
Through sexual intercourse and needle use,
but not casual office contact.
Well, the spread is not limited to sex and needle use.
That isn't true, is it, Mr. Mayfield?
Those are the most common ways it spreads.
It could spread from kissing, if there were open mouth source.
I wasn't going around kissing.
Or if people had cuts on their hands.
I never went to work with cuts on my hands, I ...
But what if you accidentally did cut yourself?
What if you took an elbow playing basketball, got a nose bleed.
The risks you are talking about are so minimal that...
But does that mean it's your right to assume them on behalf of everybody else?
A fatal disease which is infectious,
shouldn't it be a person's right to choose
whether he plays in a sport with physical contact with you?
If I had a cut on my hand,
I probably like to know which of my colleagues at work have AIDS.
Does that make my crazy?
The problem, Mr. Berluti, is there are prejudices and bigotries
that go beyond health issues when it comes to people with AIDS.
My client didn't fire you, did he?
No.
Mr. Young. Mr. Young, ....
Excuse us, no occasion.
Her name was Hilary Brandon.
She was a second year copywriter at Rogers&Cole.
She worked downtown and would like to walk home after work
to her town house in the south end.
Friends describe her in many wonderful ways.
But generous and charitable are two words
that had become almost synonymous with her name.
She would never pass a homeless person without offering something.
That was said by her roommate.
Well, she should have passed this one, ladies and gentlemen.
The evidence will show that Alex Dickson raped and strangled Hilary Brandon,
strangled her to death.
The evidence will show that this man continued to rape her
after she was dead.
He was still on top of her lifeless body raping the corpse
when Officer Mark Fryerson discovered him.
This is...
This is the ugly part of criminal law.
We deal with crimes that...
Fortunately,
at least this one is simple.
I won't have to take up too much of your time with the ugliness.
The ugly part of criminal law is when you convict the wrong person.
Alex Dickson had sex with Hilary Brandon's lifeless body,
but he didn't kill her.
You are certainly entitled to be disgusted by this man,
but you can't convict him of murder unless the evidence supports that finding,
and it won't,
because somebody else killed Hilary Brandon.
It wasn't Alex Dickson.
How long after you got the call did you find him?
About an hour, maybe a little less.
There is a back alley behind Washington.
It is in it.
I decided to go and check it.
And what did you find?
I heard some activity over behind a large dumpster.
I headed that way, shined my light,
there he was.
There who was?
Him. The defendant.
Could you see what he was doing?
He was engaging sexual intercourse with a nude female body.
I ordered him to get off the woman,
lie on the ground, face down,
at which point I handcuffed him.
I then went to check on the woman.
She was dead.
Did you check to see whether the body was warm or cold?
It was still warm.
She was dead when you got there?
I believe so.
Did you see my client kill her?
No, I did not.
But she hadn't been dead for very long…
Excuse me. Did you see my client kill her?
No.
Any thumb or finger prints or bruise, indentations
that matched up with my client?
No.
You also noted the woman smelled of garbage?
Yes.
Any idea how she got this smell?
She was probably in the dumpster.
Thank you, officer.
I think she was hiding in the dumpster, get away from him.
Why not you argue that then?
Can't prove it.
Steak are so tough.
You guys set a date yet?
June 17th. Invitations get next week.
OK. And now how soon after before we have a little Bobby?
You will be the first to know, Helen.
Of course, I will.
May I ask you guys something?
A wedding? A baby?
She has already got me pregnant.
How do you take these cases and go home?
Judge assigned it, Helen.
I know. But you could...
What's the point?
I didn't mean anything, Eugene.
I was just asking...
I'm sick of people asking that question.
It's a stupid question. We get it everywhere we go.
You think about that?
I don't expect to be getting it from a DA.
Eugene.
Especially when we are supposed to be having a nice dinner as friends.
OK. Sorry.
Excuse me.
This eyewitness is pretty much their whole case, so if there is...
He is a liar.
Billy Vicks hasn’t told the truth his whole life, about nothing.
If I hadn't found that girl first,
he would have been right there digging his poke.
You can quote me on that.
I don't believe I will.
Alex, we need facts and truth about Mr. Vicks.
He's a liar. That's a fact.
Yes.
Can you give us specific incidence of his lie?
Right here. He is lying about this.
OK.
We will see you in the court room.
he lie about this..
digging his poke if he found. of jealousy
We can go with that, Eugene.
The eyewitness is motivated by jealousy
because he didn't get to take his poke with the corpse.
This is all funny to you？
What am I missing, Eugene?
You’ve made a career out of defending dirt bags. What's changed?
Maybe I am getting sick of it.
Sharon and I split again.
I'm sorry.
When?
3 days ago.
Kendall asked me the same question Helen did last night,
and I couldn't answer it.
when she asked me later, we got into this big fight and,
here I am.
Look, I could handle this case alone, maybe that...
I'm gonna win, Lindsay.
Make no mistake about that.
We better get in.
I was at the corner of Washington and Boylston.
It was about 8:30 or so.
At night?
Yes.
That’s when I saw him.
Him being the defendant?
That’s correct.
And he was with the woman.
What woman, sir?
Hilary Brandon. I identified her from the photographs.
Could you tell what they were doing?
Talking. I assume Alex was asking her for money.
Were they arguing or …?
No, no, no.
As a matter of fact, she was smiling.
Do you know the defendant?
Oh yes. I met him on the street many times.
And you are definitely sure it was him,
this man talking to Hilary Brandon that night?
I’m positive.
And you are sure it was around 8:30?
Yes, I am.
Thank you.
What were you doing on the streets at 8:30, Mr. Vicks?
I was soliciting clients.
Soliciting clients?
You were panhandling.
That’s what some people call it.
You pretty much live on the streets?
I do.
Did the prosecution buy you those nice clothes?
Objection!
When the witness testifies he puts his demeanor into evidence.
And this witness has had part of his demeanor paid for by the prosecution.
And exactly where did the defendant’s outfit come from?
From a charity who helps innocent people
wrongly charged with crimes.
-Objection! Move to strike! -All right, all right!
That’s enough.
We will have no more discussion as to wardrobe.
The jury will not give any weights to the clothes.
You were arrested the night of the murder, weren’t you, Mr. Vicks?
Yes. But much later.
Drug and disorderly conduct?
I was sober when I saw your client with…
How many times have you been arrested for drug and disorderly conduct, sir?
Objection!
Overruled.
More than five?
Maybe.
More than ten?
I don’t know.
In fact, this was your eleventh time.
And after the last one you were told the next one meant jail time.
Isn’t that right, Mr. Vicks?
Yes.
Are you going to be serving time for your eleventh arrest?
I don’t think so.
Because you had something to offer, didn’t you, Mr. Vicks?
You decided to hand over Mr. Dickson in exchange for serving no time.
Is that why you made this story up?
Objection!
Overruled.
Did you make up this story, Mr. Vicks?
No!
They needed to place my client with the victim alive.
And you decide to offer your services, didn’t you?
I’m not lying.
I saw him with that woman.
But you did make a deal in exchange for this testimony,
didn’t you, Mr. vicks?
Yes.
And you say you were sober when you saw my client with Miss Brandon.
Was that your testimony?
Yes.
Well, according to three different witnesses,
you were seen drinking as early as four o’clock that afternoon.
But I wasn’t drunk.
You are an alcoholic, aren’t you, Mr. Vicks?
Well, I like to drink, yeah.
But why that makes me alcoholic?
Nothing further.
You’ve known he had AIDS for three years?
Yes. And I kept the secret.
Well, what changed?
I saw on the news.
These two guys stopped to help this guy in a car accident.
He wasn’t breathing.
They both did mouth to mouth.
turned out the accident victim had AIDS.
And now these two Samaritans are at risk.
They have to go for AIDS test for the next few years.
So I thought what if something like that happens here.
Suppose Wayne has heart attack, or he blacks out.
It certainly is possible given his immune system.
And then suppose somebody at work goes to resuscitate him?
Wouldn’t I be a little bit liable?
I know he has AIDS. I don’t tell?
There are people who work for me.
So you felt it was your legal responsibility?
And my moral one, to be honest.
I put my trust in these people.
And I asked these people to trust me.
How can I sit on information
that could possibly threaten their lives?
Did any doctor advise you
that Mr. Mayfield might be a health risk to anybody else?
No.
Did any medical professional advise you to reveal my client’s condition?
But probably because doctors are more afraid of being sued than anybody.
Did you consider the possibility
that Mr. Mayfield maybe stigmatized by your memo,
that he might suffer from discrimination as a result of this disclosure?
Yes.
But I weigh that risk against the potentially fatal one facing the others.
And I made my decision.
I’d also like to say I feel that
the company supported me.
He resent sympathy as he stated in his testimony.
And a lot of the discrimination he says he was subjected to,
The bulk of it he only perceived.
The employees at Straub like him.
Following my disclosure,
nobody came to me asking that he be let go.
And I think that needs to be said.
You said it perfectly.
How is it going?
He totally stunned them. Now they are willing to take 125,000.
Really?
We rejected it.
You should have seen them.
Is the Jury still out?
No.
We go back in there at five for closing argument
which I get to get work on.
Come on.
How about when I said it was the moral thing?
Did you see his face when I said that?
Did I see it?
I can hear it when that hit the floor.
He was so cocky.
That’s the way they are, Jimmy, I am telling you.
They get all these special treatment,
and they get all these special laws passed,
they get the whole country screaming let them get married.
I mean, it’s like they're some privileged class or something.
**, it's out of control.
He thinks he is smarter than everybody too.
That’s why they thought they'd win this.
Ever tell you my mother was gay, Peter?
What?
Funny.
No. It’s true.
Maybe I didn’t mention it
because I didn’t think it was such a big deal
that it would matter to my friends.
All right, Jimmy. **
Come on, you know me.
I got no problem of people living the way they want.
It’s just…
as you know.
The special treatment.
Yes.
Well, I better work on my closing.
You know what you're gonna say?
I have an idea.
Body cools down about 1 degree per hour in 65 degree weather,
which was that evening.
And we recorded a base temperature of 95.5.
That was just after midnight.
Competing the 1 degree per hour,
we calculated the time of death to be between 9 and 10 o’clock.
Since the officer found the dead at 9:30,
we determined the TOD to be between 9 and 9:30.
Were you able to determine the cause of death, Dr. Fine?
It's asphyxiation, caused by strangulation.
Between 9:00 and 9:30,
so Miss Brandon could have been killed at 9:01, possible?
Possible.
So my client’s contention that he found the body already dead around 9:15
then preceded to make love with it after she was dead,
that’s possible, isn’t it?
It’s possible, but it’s…
Well in fact, scientifically you can’t rule out that possibility at all?
No, I can’t rule it out.
In fact, a body temperature will **
if a person was struggling prior to death, wouldn’t it?
She could have been 100 when she died, isn’t that possible?
Yes.
So she might have been killed as early as 7, 7:30?
Well, a witness saw her alive at 8:30.
So you based your findings
in part on the reliability of the witness Billy Vicks?
Yes, I am.
Thank you, Dr. Fine.
The witness may step down.
Miss Gamble?
The prosecution rest, your honor.
Mr. Young, your're on.
The defense rests, your honor.
How do you mean I don’t testify?
I mean you don’t testify.
What’s with that? If I don’t tell my side,…
If we put you on the stand, all your other felonies come in,
including the time you flash kids at an elementary school.
That doesn’t make me a killer.
It makes you a piece of crap which we don’t need the jury to hear.
They already think that.
I slept with that woman.
You take the stand, they’ll know it.
OK！All right!
I don’t like this. What’s going on?
You have to trust us on this, Mr. Dickson.
I don’t put on any defence. What the hell was that?
You don’t have any defence.
You were caught red handed raping the victim.
After she was dead.
Alex, the jury won’t believe you.
How do you know?
Because I don’t believe you.
Eugene!
I think you did it.
You strangled and raped her, that’s what I think.
Because I have the pleasure of listening to your talk,
I don’t want the Jury to hear you open your fat mouth,
coz they’ll know you did it, just like I do.
I have an obligation to protect you, Alex,
and your fat mouth.
You listen to me!
Don’t you wanna mess with me!
Eugene, stop it!
Mr. Dickson,
our defense is the state hasn’t satisfied its burden of proof.
With that strategy, it’s better not to call in any witnesses.
That’s why we are not calling you.
Certainly it’s your right to testify.
And if you insist, we will allow you to do so.
But it’s our collective judgment.
It’s better for us to rest without putting on a defense,
and focus the jury on the state’s failure to make its burden.
And as it stands, we have a very good chance.
I don’t know what’s going on,
but gay bashing seems to become back to style.
We got radio talk show’s hosts proudly
declaring their prejudices,
churches and politicians calling gay people sick,
voters coming out and droves to support bans on gay marriages…
What is going on?
As far as fear of AIDS goes,
you want something really to be scared about?
Abolish people’s right to medical privacy,
and they simply won’t get tested.
They will stop going to the doctors,
then watch the disease spread, many diseases.
This man went and got tested,
and he was punished for it.
Is that the message we want to be sending?
Because if that’s it, then a plague on all our houses.
What was he talking about?
Gay backlash?
Gays have got more special treatment going than anybody.
We got special AIDS laws.
Hollywood, the army, the Oscars,
they all got those red ribbons on, don’t they,
in honor of AIDS?
My dad died of a heart attack.
Where is the ribbon for cardiovascular disease?
And now, when a person has a fatal deadly infectious disease,
there is a law that says you can’t even warn people.
Nobody say we should discriminate against people with AIDS,
but where is the law to protect you and me?
Where is the legislation to protect Mr. Mayfield’s coworkers?
If he dropped, a dozen different people would be giving him mouth to mouth.
If he got cut playing basketball,
his teammate would help attend to it.
They don’t have a right to know they could be risking their lives?
How not is that?
Doesn’t Mr. Hines own some duty
to look out for the people who work for him?
He did the moral thing, the reasonable thing.
And let’s remind ourselves one more time,
the plaintiff didn’t get fired, nobody beat him up.
Mr. Mayfield says he even felt depressed by the people
who were trying to help him, for God’s sakes.
Maybe we should pass another law.
It’s a crime to show too much sympathy for people with AIDS.
Enough is enough.
How are we doing?
I think we are OK.
How are you doing?
I’m fine, Lindsay.
Eugene.
Don’t start playing psychologist with me, OK?
Are you seeing any psychologist?
Because I think you should be.
Is that right?
Yes.
Every time you take cases like this,
you just, you turn angry.
-I mean the …beat up at court. -It doesn’t have to be fun, Lindsay.
What am I supposed to do?
Be all happy, Lindsay?
These cases don’t bother me, OK?
Whatever you're feeling…
I don’t feel anything. I am a defense attorney.
It’s not my job to feel.
Why can’t people see that?
I have work to do, Lindsay.
I think I should do the closing.
I will do it.
If you can’t do your best…
I will do my very best.
Cases like this…
I guess I'm afraid I'll let my personal disgust affect my head.
I compensate by trying harder.
If anything I tried even harder for the guilty.
How sick is that?
They've reached a verdict already?
I’m on my way.
Jimmy, my spies at the courthouse said your closing seemed a little rednecked?
I went and I thought what I said would be effective.
Red neck?
Red, white, and blue.
I better go.
If there is a question defense attorneys get asked
more than anything else,
it’s how can you do it.
How can you walk in the court day after day after day
defending the scum of the earth,
then go home and sleep?
Well, I got myself a pretty good piece of scum in this one, don’t I?
He raped a dead woman.
Hard enough for me to even look at him, let along defend him.
But the answer to the question is
I don’t come in here day after day representing people like him.
I represent you and me.
I’m in here making sure the prosecution lives up to its burden
of proving guilty beyond reasonable doubt
before they get to incarcerate people.
Because if they don’t live up to their burden,
if we start letting them convict without meeting that criteria,
then innocent people are at risk,
you and me,
maybe him too.
I don’t know.
Maybe he killed that woman, maybe he didn’t.
I can’t tell you.
What I can say is they didn’t satisfy their burden.
There is doubt all over the place.
Nobody saw him commit a murder.
The coroner himself said the murder could have happened
hours before the police officer found him.
It’s not likely he is gonna hang around with this victim for hours, is he?
No thumb prints and bruises around the neck matches my client.
The victim smelled like garbage, why?
Because she was in that dumpster,
just like my client said she was when he found her.
One witness who places my client with the victim alive
turns out to be a drunk,
likely drunk at the time.
Can we really trust his powers of observation?
or his creditability?
The testimony he gave was part of a deal that kept him out of jail.
Deal…
What I should say is bribe,
he had a motive to lie.
Now the only thing they can prove
is that my client was having sex with that dead body.
Does that make him wild? Absolutely.
But it in no way proves he committed a homicide.
It certainly doesn’t prove it beyond reasonable doubt.
Miss Gamble started things off calling this ugly.
It is ugly. Sometimes, the job is ugly.
I got to come in here and fight for a system I believe in
even I don’t like my client.
And it gets ugly for juries, too.
Because doing your job here means finding that man not guilty,
it absolutely means that under the facts we had.
Now I can’t stop you from saying, the hell with the rules.
I can’t prevent you from lowing the burden of prove,
if that's what you choose to do.
I will ask you to consider.
What if one day you, or somebody you love
is charged with a crime you or he didn’t commit,
how would you feel if you, he, or she got a jury
who dispense with the burden of prove
and just said, close enough.
It happens.
Those are against every grain of our criminal justice system,
but it happens,
violate every principle of our constitution,
but it happens.
The only question we have here is
is it going to happen today.
It is possible that he did find her dead.
It is possible.
There is nothing they can do to disprove that possibility,
definitely not beyond reasonable doubt.
That’s a fact, a fact you can take back into that room.
In order for the system to work,
we need the defense attorneys to do their job
even when it is unpopular to do so.
In order for the system to work,
we need the juries to do their jobs.
Like Miss Gamble said,
sometimes the job is ugly.
Very few cases is the defendant actually seen committing a murder.
The jury is allowed to consider circumstantial evidence
when making its finding.
Here, the defendant was found raping the victim
while her body was still warm.
Our system of criminal justice doesn’t preclude you from using common sense.
Anything is possible, ladies and gentlemen.
And our burden…
it isn’t proved beyond all doubt.
It’s proved beyond all reasonable doubt.
He was seen with her alive.
He was discovered with her dead.
Gee, I wonder what happened.
In the matter of Mayfield vs. Straub Industries,
we find in favor of the plaintiff Wayne Mayfield
and order the defendant to pay damages
in the amount of 25 dollars.
Jury is dismissed with the thanks of the court.
We are adjourned.
Did he say 25 dollars?
Yeah.
We won basicly.
Yeah, you did, Peter.
You are a big winner.
It was your closing, Jimmy.
Well, you inspired it.
You got something to say?
Yeah. I think you are a bigot.
I also think you revealing his condition,
you probably meant to create a climate
that will make him want to leave.
Mission accomplished, Pete.
Growing up, you thought they were just as sick as I did.
Come on.
The difference is I grew up.
Did I handle myself OK?
You did great. I got goose bumps.
I was suddenly proud to be a defense attorney again.
That’s for sure, you should be proud.
Do you really mean that?
You know…
we are trained not to ask ourselves a big question,
how can you defend murderers and rapists.
We’re trained not to go near there because if we do,
we will end up in mess.
So, we stay away, far away,
until one day we don’t even recognize the question.
And when people ask us, we were just act like you don’t get it.
So, maybe they are the ones that lost.
And it hits you.
Maybe we are the ones who lost.
There is honor in what you do, Eugene.
You may not believe your own words in there.
But I do.
She said I can’t feel.
Who?
Sharon.
And she's right.
I can’t feel.
I’m afraid to let myself feel.
Maybe that’s why I can be so damn honorable.
Lock up when you go?
Yeah.
Hey, mom.
No.
I'm still at the office, just getting ready to leave.
Oh, you got accompany?
I’ll let you go.
No, no, nothing’s wrong.
I was just calling to say Hi, that's all.
How is everything going?
Yeah. Same.
Pretty normal.
No, no, nothing is wrong.
I was just calling
let you know I was thinking of you, that's all.
Well, we'll talk tomorrow.
All right.
Love you, too.
Will the defendant please rise?
Has the jury reached its verdict?
We have, your honor.
What say you?
Account 32623 on the charge of murder in the first degree,
we found the defendant Alex Dickson
not guilty.
On the account of murder in the second degree,
we found the defendant
not guilty.
On the account of lascivious and unnatural acts,
we found the defendant
guilty.
The defendant is sentenced 6 months.
Credited with time served, he is free to go.
Let’s conclude the jury's service.
We are adjourned.
I don't believe it. I don't believe it.
So, can I go?
Check with probation and you can go.