Can you draft up a motion to compel on Peters?
Documents?
Yeah.
Bobby, you ready?
Ready?
To go to the printers for the invitations?
Oh God, I completely forgot!
I got the Strauss depo at 10.
Discovery's over on Peters?
But we still don't have the medicals.
You promised!
Strauss, that jerk?
That client.
I'm sorry.
You should move for sanctions.
I'll never get that...
You scheduled this depo intentionally.
I didn't!
At least try.
Can you at least look?
-Parchment with black ink or white with embossing?  -Yes on sanctioning, Bobby?
-Uh... yes.   -The embossing is nice.
I didn't ask you.
Bobby, you're going to be late.
Here's Strauss' address.
Bobby!
Uh... white with the gold border.
That wasn't one of the choices!
You asked my opinion.
Doesn't mean she wanted it...
White with the gold.
He didn't even look.
They never give you sanctions.
You ever get sanctions?
Here's the keys.
That ain't gonna do it.
Here's my wallet...
That ain't gonna do it, either.
Maybe you didn't see the gun, huh?
Take my watch.ATM card.
whatever, whatever you want.
I want you, Bobby Donnell.
I came for you.
本集英文剧本来自网络
时间轴：美溪客
Over there!
Look pal, I don't know what you want...
Sit down.
Sit your ass down!
Do me a favor too, okay?
Don't call me pal.
I want you to call me Mr. Rooney. Okay?
Ain't that what the judge called me, huh?
Mr. Rooney?
Right before he dumped my ass in the hole for 12 years?
Rooney?
Yeah. Rooney. Patrick Rooney.
Your old client.
When?
1988. Braintree. Double homicide.
I didn't think you'd remember.
Wait a second. Rooney.
I got you a deal, didn't I?
Yeah. You got rid of me.
That's what you did.
What are you talking about?
Shut up!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Rooney. You had a trial!
Some trial.
You were really good there, too.
You sat there. You heard the evidence.
You said yourself the jury was going to convict.
I didn't force you to take any deal.
What are you talking about?
You told me it was this or life!
So I did 12 years for killings that I didn't do.
It's judgment day, Bob.
Now you're on trial.
I really hope I ordered enough invitations.
250. Lindsay,
it's a wedding, not a Celtic game.
I really don't think you should rush her.
Excuse me?
If you're not here to be helpful...
Y'know, maybe you should pretend like you have another customer.
Aren't you the witch?
How many came to your wedding?
I'm not married.
Big surprise.
That's weird.
Hey, has anyone seen Bobby?
He hasn't shown up yet for the deposition.
Well, maybe he got caught in traffic.
He left over an hour ago and he was only going to Medford.
You want to tell me what your problem is or what?
You're my problem!
That much I gather. Maybe you could be more specific.
Y'know, it would be poor judgment for you to get smug right now.
All right, look,
I'm sorry if you felt you didn't get a fair shake.
It happens sometimes.
It's not a perfect system.
Well, I got news for you.
It wasn't the system. It was you.
You may want to think that, but...
Hey, I just wanted to take the stand and tell my side of the story.
But you...you wouldn't let me.
I did that to protect you...
To protect me?
Yes. You had a list of priors.
Doesn't mean I killed anyone.
You take the stand, the priors come in.
I wasn't on trial for my priors!
That wouldn't have mattered to the jury.
They just would've concluded that...
The jury should've heard me say that I didn't kill anybody!
Instead, I sat there with my mouth shut on your advice,
and they made their own conclusions,
didn't they, counsel?
You know what really bothers me?
You know what's really been eating at me?
You never even asked to hear my side of the story.
You didn't even want to listen.
There's a reason for that.
Whatever you tell me as a client, I'm stuck with it.
If I know you're about to lie on the stand,
I have a duty to go to the judge and tell him.
It's better in some situations for the lawyer not to hear what happened!
Assuming that I would be lying. Which I wasn't.
I was gonna tell the truth.
But you refused to believe me!
Okay, Patrick.
Okay.
Tell me the story.
I stayed in the car that night.
Mickey went inside.
I had no idea what he was going to do.
I only drove him to his ex's
because he said he had some things to get back from her.
He told me he was going to talk to her.
It'd just take a few minutes,
so I waited.
All of a sudden I heard shots going off.
I didn't even know Mickey had a piece on him that night.
But you ran...
I freaked!
I turned around, I seen Mickey come out covered in blood.
I couldn't have any part of that,
so I took off, okay?
Even if that were true, we had no way of proving it.
Mickey didn't live long enough to back you.
Because the police killed him!
As I recall, they found your jacket next to the bodies
with the mother's blood all over it...
Mickey borrowed my coat!
I'm telling you, I stayed in the car!
Okay, Patrick, I believe you. I believe you.
Don't play with me. You never believed me!
Bobby? Bobby, are you there?
Bobby?
Bobby.
What?
I think he answered, but then it went dead.
Well, it probably didn't go through.
No, no. Somebody answered.
All right.
This is wrong.
It's not "Mr. and Mrs. Robert Donnell".
It's supposed to read "Ms. Lindsay Dole and Mr. Robert Donnell" on the envelopes.
What?
You're sublimating.
I'm what?
You're taking it out on the envelopes, it's very common.
Things will go a lot smoother with your second marriage.
I heat my pool on repeat business.
People actually come back to you?
You're hurtful.
And you wonder why you can't latch onto a husband.
Is that you or me?
-I got it.   -Drug dealers.
Yeah? Ugh, no I haven't heard from him.
Did you try his cell phone?
That's strange.
Okay, I'm on my way.
What is it?
Bobby never showed up for his deposition,
and no one's heard from him.
You're breathing pretty heavy, counsel.
What's the matter, you scared?
Isn't that what you want?
I'd just hate to see this gun go off by accident.
That would be ironic, wouldn't it?
See, I'm having a hard time living with your mistake,
and you certainly couldn't live with mine.
Patrick, however angry you are,
you're free now. You're out.
Why throw that all away?
Hey. It was all thrown away the day you were assigned to me.
Fine. So now what,
you're gonna kill me and go back to prison?
Your life will be over.
Let me tell you something, Bobby.
The only thing that's kept me going is hate.
Knowing that if I just stuck it out,
I would get the chance to have this very moment right here.
That's the only thing I've had to cling to for the past 12 years.
Now that might not seem like much to most people.
But for me? To have the chance to kill you...
If that were it, you would have done it.
Oh, it'll happen.
But first, you're gonna face the facts.
The facts that could've cleared me.
The facts that you ignored.
And then I'll kill you.
-Nobody at all?  -He's about 6'1",
-Maybe he came in with a head injury.  -dark brown hair, blue eyes.
An amnesia thing.
-He could've come in as a John Doe.  -Yes, Donnell is the last name.
-No?  -Yeah, sure, I'll hold again.
Ok, thanks. Nothing from Mass General.
Ditto from Tufts New England.
And they're still saying his cell phone is out of range and not turned on.
Any news?
Nothing. He hasn't shown up at a hospital.
Did you call the police?
Not yet.
Why not?
Lindsay, I'm on it.
Get Maguire. I'll talk to him.
Excuse me, one second, ok?
Lindsay, I'm on the phone with Bobby's credit card company.
They're saying something about him buying electronics equipment.
DVD player, wide screen TV..
Hello, this is Lindsay Dole
I'm Mr. Donnell's fiancee.
Is the person using Mr. Donnell's credit card
still at the electronics store?
Then get them to hold him.
What do you mean, you can't?
He's got his card!
Look, this is Helen Gamble of the Suffolk County District Attorney's office.
I need you to talk to your manager.
Tell him to have security hold the man until the police...
I don't care what your policy is!
Do what I say or I will charge you with obstruction of justice.
Give me the number of the store.
Y'know, I can still remember the first time you came to see me in the lockup.
You walked in real sharp.
I figured "Great. Some big Harvard type attorney. No problem."
Did you go to Harvard, Bobby?
Hey. I asked you a question.
I went to Suffolk.
Suffolk? That's a race track.
Look, what the hell do you want from me?
I've been sitting here for three hours...
You son of a bitch! I'd kill you right now if I wasn't...
What? If you weren't what?
You just shut up.
You just shut your face and sit there!
You'll see what.
I told ya, I told ya, and I told ya.
I lifted the cards from the guy's wallet.
It was just laying there.
Lying where?
Is this some kind of trick? I already said!
Then tell us again, Mr. Franco.
In the parking structure, on the ground, second level.
And you didn't roll the guy?
You never saw Mr. Donnell at all?
Come on, detective.
You got my record right there in front of you.
I boost and fence.
Sometimes I kite a few checks,
but I don't break heads!
I just took the guy's cards.
You don't live here, do you?
Yeah, I do.
Having trouble walking lately?
That's my grandfather's.
Does he know what you're doing here?
No. He died the week before I got out of jail.
Were you two close?
Are we bonding now?
You stay right there.
I got nothing to loose.
Don't be jumping to any conclusions.
This can be very misleading.
Helen, we've been to crime scenes before.
You sure you want to be here?
I could take you back to the office.
No. I'll be all right.
What do you got?
Not much.
Carjacking?
Possible.
But most of those guys total the vehicle before they kick it back.
And looking at the blood on the hood...
I know. But I want the facts before I go there.
We'll do a typing.
Mike.
Hey, Eugene.
Lindsay.
Do you have any witnesses?
We're talking to people now, but I want to be realistic.
Meaning what, exactly?
They're not big on neighborhood watch in this part of town.
Most of the guys down here...
They see a uniform, they think it's coming for them.
Do what you have to do to get answers.
I'll look the other way if I have to.
Sit right there.
What's going on, Patrick? Who is he?
You wanna know who he is?
Tell him who you are.
Please, I don't know what this is all about..
Tell him!
Seymour Sternbach.
Look, if I did something, I...
That's enough.
I don't get it, Patrick.
What's going on?
Seymour Sternbach.
What, that doesn't ring any bells to you, counsel?
This is my exculpatory witness.
Your what?
The man who could've cleared me!
The man that you said you couldn't find.
The man that I found three days after I got out of prison!
The man you never even bothered to look for.
Kidnapped?
Yeah. That's what they think.
By who?
They haven't figured that part out yet.
Random, or do they think he was the target?
I don't know, it could be either.
They really just don't know very much!
Kidnapped?
So, what, they expect us to get a ransom call?
Kidnapped for money?
I don't know.
I swear, I don't remember!
You're lying. You remember!
I don't!
You were there, Seymour.
In a car, driving by, who would remember?
I remember. We talked that night.
Yeah. You and me. We spoke.
You were looking for a parking space.
I flagged you down,
I told you I'd just be a minute,
I was only waiting for my buddy.
And then we talked about your red mustang.
Then you saw another space open up,
so you took that one instead.
Look, who's going to remember a two minute conversation
over a parking spot 12 years ago?
It was all over the news. The very next day.
A double homicide right where you were,
and you're going to sit here and tell me you don't remember?
I don't!
Patrick!
Don't lie to me.
Don't you lie to me.
Patrick, you're gonna kill him!
Tell the truth. Tell the truth!
All right.
Tell him.
I was there.
You remember talking to him?
Yes.
The night of the murder?
Why didn't you come forward?
I was...
Look, I'm a married man. I met a girl.
-If I'd come forward, things would have been...  -Hey, hey.
I did 12 years.
You let me do 12 years because you were cheating on your wife?
Hey, for all I know,
you could've killed those people after we talked!
Patrick!
And you, you should've found him.
Even if we had found him, he doesn't get you off at all!
Yes he does!
No! He just confirms that you were at the scene
ready to drive the getaway car!
That's all the jury needs!
Only if I knew!
I told you that I had no idea what the hell Mickey was gonna do.
Even so..
Intent, counsel. Intent.
Look it up. I did.
Mens Reus.
If I didn't know what he was gonna do...
But you helped him get away!
He never got in the car!!
But still, it was only your word!
Why would I flag a guy down if I was there to commit a crime?
Never thought about that, did you, counsel?
See that look on your face?
That's the look of a guilty man.
What about previous threats?
Did Bobby have any recent run-ins with clients
or witnesses that might have a vendetta?
We usually win.
No threats? No client you've screwed over?
What? I didn't screw anybody over.
We may have got a break.
What?
Match on the prints from Bobby's car.
Name's Rooney. Patrick Kevin Rooney.
Patrick Rooney...
I think we had a client with that name,
but that was a long time ago.
Makes sense. He just finished 12 years at Cedar Junction.
A manslaughter deal.
I remember it because I'd just started working here.
I think he's from Southie.
We're going over his full history now,
but we'll need anything you still have.
Okay. Okay, maybe I should have found him.
You screwed up. You screwed up!
And if I did? It's too late to change the past.
You want me to try and get the record expunged?
You know what's been expunged?
The past 12 years of my life.
Enough about the 12 years.
I've heard about the 12 years.
What about the 10 years before that?
When you were out committing aggrevated assault
and knocking off liquor stores,
the 10 years before that.
That's the reason why I didn't out you in the witness chair.
The 10 years before that...
Was the reason you assumed that I was guilty!
Maybe it was and I'm to blame.
But so are you.
Who you were went into my thinking.
What you were.
You have to take some kind of responsibility for that!
You sit tight.
Don't try anything cute.
Hey.
Okay, Patrick. You got five minutes.
Why don't you come inside?
I'm serious, Patrick.
I told you on the phone I've got nothing else to say.
**
no, no, no!
Patrick!
Listen, I'm sorry.
But I can't let you leave.
Patrick...
Come on, come on.
Oh my God!
Come on, Suzie.
-Patrick, no!   -Come on.
-Patrick, please..   -Sit. Sit down.
Listen. Hey.
Look,I don't want you to see me like this the first time,
but I don't have any choice now.
What are you talking about?
I had to make you see.
Because of them, I lost you.
I lost everything.
What?
They'll tell you I'm innocent.
You tell her what happened.
He's... he's innocent.
Patrick, why are you doing this?
Suzie, please.
I'm not going to hurt you, I promise.
Please. Stay right here, okay?
Relax, okay?
I'm gonna get you something to drink.
I'll get you some tonic, all right?
You want some chips?
You've got two men at gunpoint and you're offering me chips?
Come on, Patrick. Leave her out of this.
Leave her out of it?
Leave her out of this?
She is the reason you're here right now,
and she is the only reason you're still alive!
You understand me?
It has to be here.
Nice filing system you had, Bec.
Y'know, I don't see any dates on these folders.
Keep looking.
What exactly are we looking for again?
Court docs, work products,
list of personal contacts,
anyone or anything that might help us.
We're going to be here all night.
I don't know why we're so shocked this happened.
The people we have as clients...
All right, Ellenor.
No, I'm serious, Eugene.
Clients always blame their lawyers, even in civil cases.
Our clients are murderers half the time going in.
The bigger surprise is that it doesn't happen more often.
I don't think she needed to hear that.
I am sure he is okay.
You can't be sure of that.
I mean, who are we kidding?
If this is a revenge thing,
the likelihood is he's dead.
We both know it.
We don't know anything.
This doesn't fit the typical...
We haven't heard from him.
I mean, this Rooney guy?
I mean, why would he be taking him hostage?
We both know the statistics, Helen.
And the longer he's missing...
We'll find him.
I... I don't...
I don't know if I can handle this, Helen.
We'll find him.
Got it!
Rooney had us send a copy of his appelment papers
to his grandfather, Seamus Rooney.
The address is right there.
All right, let's call Maguire.
I have two backup cars there right now and a couple on the way.
No one makes a move until we get there, understood?
Helen! I'm going with you.
We're all going.
Let's just go.
You want a drink, Suzie?
I got it.
I thought you knew.
Who was I kidding, huh?
12 years, you don't come to see me once.
I should've figured it out, huh?
I loved you, Patrick.
What kind of a future did I have with you?
Especially after...
You got kids?
Two.
Pictures?
Yeah.
That's Jake.
He's 7.
And that's Johnny.
He's 3.
They're beautiful.
I...
I wish you could've stuck by me.
Helped me through the trial.
We've known each other what, since seventh grade?
You don't even come to see me at the trail?
She was a character witness, Patrick.
Her testimony wasn't important.
Hey, it was important to me!
She knew me.
I thought if I could make anyone understand it would have been you.
Now look at her.
We were gonna get married.
Now she's afraid to even sit down and have a conversation with me.
This could have been my life.
Patrick Rooney! This is the Boston PD!!
No one will get hurt if you do as we say!
Hey, I got people in here!
That's him. Rooney.
Let's talk this out, Patrick.
Tell me what's going on.
Oh my God!
Are you okay?
We're all right.
How many are you?
Three!
Hold it right there.
I said get back!
I'm not armed, Patrick.
See?
You heard me. Get back!
Come on, Patrick. I want to help you.
Tell me what you want, we'll work it out.
Talk to him.
You shut up.
It's not too late to end this all peacefully.
Come on, Patrick. You can get out of all this.
Tell him you want an offer.
What are you talking about? No!
Talk deal and we'll consider!
Bobby
A deal! Give us something to work with!
You speaking for Rooney?
-Yes!   -No! No!
Let's get the snipers in place.
It's still unclear as to when the hostages were abducted.
Our sources say it began in the morning.
We do know that the suspect's name is Patrick Kevin Rooney,
released just three days ago from Cedar Junction,
after serving 12 years for a double homicide.
One of the hostages is Robert Donnell,
the attorney of record who handled Mr. Rooney's murder trail 12 years ago.
Yeah, mishandled is more like it.
Patrick, you gotta decide what you wanna do here.
What do you want me to do?
You want me to make a deal, huh, Bobby?
You want me to make a deal so you can go on with your life?
Not this time. No deals!
Can't you see the man's trying to help you, Patrick?
Or what, you wanna die here in your grandfather's house?
Real nice for his memory.
You had a clear shot there, why didn't you take it?
-We try to negotiate first before shooting him.  -Yeah, but how long do you plan...
Helen, please?
This isn't good. The guy isn't even making any demands.
Which means?
Which means he probably hasn't got a plan,
which means he's probably out of control.
They should just take him out.
Well, let's hope they can.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
Not like this.
Patrick, are you listening to me?
Come out now and we'll work something out. I promise.
He promised!
Shut up, you!
Patrick, your mission here, as I understand it,
was to show me and Suzie that you didn't do the crime.
To convince me that I screwed up by not believing you
and finding this witness.
You've done all this!
That was only half of my mission.
The other half was to kill you.
Then do it!
And get it over with!
Fine.
Don't antagonize him, for God's sake!
In which case the police will be charging in to shoot you!
Stop it!
There is a way out. Let me talk to them.
If I can get you out of this, Patrick,
let me try. Let me try.
No.
You don't want to die in here, Patrick.
You can't want to die.
Patrick.
All right. Let's go.
You stay where I can see you.
You hear me?
Hold up, everybody. Hold up!
Hold up.
We're ready to talk.
All right, Bobby. Go to the phone.
Not you, Mike.
Someone who can make good.
Everyone goes free in exchange for charges dropped.
Bobby
Helen, that's the way it's gotta be.
Can he hear us?
No.
That's the offer.
All right.
Tell him to send out the hostages and we will drop all charges.
That won't work. You gotta do better than that.
Ugh. All right, all right.
Tell him we'll keep the parole violation.
Suspended sentence.
Whatever.
You're not listening.
He isn't doing time!
We agree to no time or there's no deal.
The guy's got a gun, he's about to shoot me.
Okay, uh, I'm juts gonna keep talking so it looks like we're responding.
Uh, Lindsay's doing okay,
we're all taking care of her. Bobby,
we'll get you out.
That's the only deal we're making.
Okay. Here's the offer.
They won't file on kidnaping, assault, or false imprisonment.
But the parole violation stands.
No.
Patrick, this is on the news.
They can't just tell the public they let you walk free!
I have Helen Gamble's word
she will agree to a suspended sentence on the parole violation,
so in essence, you will be walking free.
No judge is going to sign off on that!
The judge will go along if we can show you were wrongly accused.
We'll need you for that.
Fine.
You can get out of all this, Patrick.
All of it.
It's not too late.
No. I want your life ruined.
I want your life ruined just like you ruined mine.
Patrick, you want the world to know that you're not a murderer.
I won't go back to prison?
No.
You leave last.
We're told the police have made dialogue with the suspect
and an arrangement may have been made to release the hostages.
What is happening?
I'm not sure.
Who's he?
I have no idea.
All right, Suzie.
Bye.
I didn't do it.
I know, Patrick.
I know.
I'm sorry.
Maybe I'll meet your kids someday, huh?
All right.
Get out of here.
You got a girl?
Engaged.
She's out there...scared to death.
She's special, huh?
Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry.
I should've found that witness.
I'm sorry.
You talked about the 10 years before. My priors.
The last two, I was clean.
I was getting my life together.
Maybe I could've been a lawyer or something, who knows.
Any deal hold on,
It really wouldn't matter what the DA was offering in terms of a plea.
They could, in effect, promise the suspect anything under the sun
and then vitiate the deal on grounds of duress.
So what's interesting...
What does vitiate mean?
What the hell does vitiate mean?
There's no deal, is there?
You've screwed me again.
The DA, she agreed...
Is there a deal or not?!
There's a deal.
Bobby. Bobby!
Get her out of here!
We can't tell exactly what's going on,
but we just heard the sound of gunfire coming from within the house,
where the gunman is still holding Bobby Donnell, the Boston attorney.
Sierra one, if you can get a shot.
Patrick!
Patrick, if you could hear me...
Dial the number.
Patrick, pick up the phone.
I need you to answer the phone!
Anybody does anything, and he dies!
Patrick...
Shut up!
You hear me?
What do you want?
I want you to send in the DA.
And only her.
Patrick, we can't!
I know she's out there. Send her in!
You got a shot?
Barely.
Patrick, release Mr. Donnell and we'll send in the DA.
No. No way.
Patrick, please!
You send her in right now, or he dies!
If you release Mr. Donnell...
He dies on the count of 3.
Do you understand me?
Let me go.
-Not a chance.  -One.
Patrick!
Two.
Take him.
One single gunshot wound to the head,
Mr. Rooney went down immediately.
The hostage, Robert Donnell, was unhurt.
Patrick Kevin Rooney was pronounced dead on the scene.
Police homicide detective Mike Maguire spoke later about the incident.
I did screw up his case.
Bobby...
I was right out of school.
Taking three assignments a clip, 17 hours a day,
trying to scratch.
I trusted the DAs then.
If they told me he was guilty, I believed them.
I probably did push that deal on him
without even bothering to track down the witness.
Took one look at his rap sheet and
prejudged him.
And I doubt...
I doubt it was the only time.
I thought I'd lost you.
The whole time, all I could see was your face.
It's over.
Your face.
And all I can see now...
is his.