Previous on The Practice:
Did you murder her because she was gonna break up a sexual affair?
I did not have an affair with her and I did not kill her.
You’re going down for murder now, you get that?
It was Steven.
Your son Steven?
I saw the door closed on him when he left.
Why haven’t you told anybody these?
Because I don’t want him to spend the rest of his life in jail
for something I drove him to.
Let me go to the DA.
Absolutely not.
This is between you and me, you gave me your word.
We find the defendant guilty.
I didn’t do it. I didn’t do it.
Your dad saw you going out the door.
The reason he staying quiet
he doesn’t wanna see you go to prison.
He loves you too much for that.
Jimmy, what happened?
Steven Olson, he just hung himself in the garage.
You think I am gonna ask the judge to release a convicted murderer
on the grounds of his defence attorney says he is innocent?
I expect you to because he is innocent.
For all we know the kid hung himself because his father is a killer.
That isn’t the case.
Well give me evidence.
Henry.
Hey.
What happened?
They tried to rape me.
Inmates?
Two of them.
I covered my ass.
But my face didn’t fare so well.
Doctor say you're ganna be okay.
I want solitary, Jimmy.
I don’t wanna be in the general population anymore.
Can you get me solitary, Jimmy?
听写：诸如
时间轴：美溪客
Richard, I wanna reopen the Henry Olson case.
On what grounds?
On the grounds he’s innocent.
Jimmy, I told you, bring me new evidence then I can do…
There is no new evidence, but that doesn’t change the truth.
The guy didn’t do it.
Okay, I got a pretrial, can we talk later?
Yeah.
Listen, if the DA goes forward…
That’s not gonna happen.
Why? Because of your conviction, right?
Because I don’t believe he’s innocent.
The case went to a verdict, the right man is serving time.
I need a favor here.
I am sorry, no.
I filed a petition to reopen.
Clyde Miller, murder in the first degree.
Hold on.
Richard Bay for the Commonwealth, Your Honour,
we oppose bail of any kind.
The suspect is obviously a flight risk, not to mention…
Is he represented?
**, we are waiting for somebody from the PD’s office.
Mr. Berluti, come meet your new client.
I am not taking appointment today, Judge.
Well I am afraid you are.
We’ll enter a not guilty for now.
Meet with Mr. Miller, then we'll conference.
Your Honour, I can’t take…
Are you in trial, Mr. Berluti?
No. but…
Then meet with Mr. Miller.
Next case. Please.
People versus Megan Baucher, solicitation and loitering.
Can I get you some more coffee?
This is my third cup. Is Mr. Bradford not available?
He’s just finishing up a conference call. He will be right…
He’s been finishing that call for some time.
We have other business scheduled for the day.
If he’s too busy…
I apologize. Thank you, Sheila.
I am sorry, Eugene, Rebecca.
I have actually been conferencing with the insurance company and Doctor Stiles.
I pushed them up to 32, that’s as far as it’ll go.
Doctor Stiles is angry to be settling at all.
32?
Yes.
32 thousand.
A man is dead; you’re offering 32 thousand dollars.
Well it’s not a question of the worth of the deceased, Eugene,
you know that, the issue is liability.
My client died on the doctor’s table.
Look, you and I could debate this **, we are never going to agree.
And my client is adamant,
so, either we are going to end this at 32 thousand
or we are going to have to let the jury decide.
We will be letting the jury decide.
I didn’t know he was a rabbi, I swear I didn’t know.
I understand this, but Clyde,
whether you knew he was a Rabbi or not
it was still illegal for you to kill him
Is that mean they're gonna get me like one of those hate crimes?
coz he’s Jewish, I get nailed with a hate crime?
Clyde, hate crime isn’t your worry;
you are up on first degree murder.
You hit a Rabbi over the head with a bat.
But don’t they gotta prove intent? My intent was to rob him.
This is prejudice. The Jewish, they get special treatment.
You think Jews get special treatment on account
you’re not being able to hit rabbis with bats?
I just meant to rob him. I was swinging him for a shoulder blade.
I am begging you.
All right, I am Jewish,I really wanna take this off your hands.
He’s not gonna hit you.
Forget it.
Lindsay.
I’ve got these depositions all week.
Oh, come on.
What’s wrong?
I am going to court tomorrow, trying to reopen on Henry Olson.
Judge just spanked me with a court appointed “lujack”
and nobody here would lend a hand
after I just flew across country to help you.
-Jimmy, I can’t. I pinch all my case before me. -I am in a **  I need some assistance.
All right, Ellenor, back him up.
-Why can’t Lindsay do it?-Why can I just give it to her?
Because it’s on the news, Jimmy.
There is a big public outcry, have you been paying attention?
Well, I got a motion to reopen on Henry Olson…
I will help on Olson, Ellenor.
Basically they are still denying blame.
The doctor evidently is reluctant to settle at all.
So what happens now?
Well, we still schedule for trial tomorrow,
you can either take the 32 which…
Well, our cost right now are running over 14,
so that plus the contingency, you get about 11.
11 thousand dollars?
You make out better than us.
Between my time and Eugene’s,
we’ve got over 14 thousand investing in this case.
So, why are we even hesitating? Let’s go to trial.
Mrs. Riley, I will be honest.
This is a very tough case to win.
Now I believe the doctor was negligent, but proving it…
I know 11 is not much, but I am sure you could use the money.
Is there a woman that you love, Mr. Young?
Yes.
Well I’ll tell you, the day comes some doctor kills her,
the day comes you have to bury her,
I don’t think you’re gonna be walking away for 11 thousand dollars
whether you could use the money or not.
How you doing?
Okay.
They’re letting me out tomorrow.
Did you get me isolation?
They stuck the guy who did this to you in a hole, Henry, so…
They'll be ** this, Jimmy.
I am a freak; I am the guy with the bug fetish.
Okay, I’ll take care of it.
Meantime,
I get a motion set tomorrow to reopen your case.
Is there any chance?
I don’t know. But I am gonna fight.
I promise you, I am gonna fight.
I…
I never told you how sorry I am that he took his life.
On account of me…
It was me.
If I hadn’t confronted him
which I had no legal right to do.
Jimmy, consider who he had for a father.
You are a good man, Henry.
You’ve always been a good man.
Your son knew that.
Yeah.
I am gonna fight.
I used to date a Jewish girl. I am not prejudiced.
I only hit the guy because he wouldn’t give me his money.
Clyde, will you get off the Jewish thing?
It don’t matter that the victim was Jewish, what matters is he’s dead.
Oh… you don’t know what this is gonna do to my parents.
They’re calling you a murderer, you think they would proud?
All right, Jimmy.
Forget that he was a rabbi.
All right.
Look, tell me what you were doing at the hour to begin with.
I was high, I was waiting to mug somebody.
But I wouldn’t hit any religion, I swear.
Guard!
Look, I am due in court in another matter,
I am gonna come back after lunch.
Don’t talk to anybody, you hear me?
Nobody.
Fine, I am not a talker.
You are a thinker.
Jimmy.
The guy’s got the IQ of a relief pitcher.
It was a birthday present.
From you to your husband?
Yes. He just couldn’t take being fat.
So as a birthday gift.
I took him to Doctor Stiles to talk about lipo suction.
And how did you hear of Doctor Stiles, Mrs. Riley?
I saw his add.
And when you went to see him?
Everything was fine.
He said my husband was a good candidate.
It was every exciting for my husband.
He couldn’t wait to do it.
So, you decided to go for the surgery.
Yes. It was just supposed to be an outpatient thing.
So, we arrived at his office at seven in the morning and at the…
the procedure started at 10.
And then at one o’clock he…hm…
the doctor came out and told me that my husband was dead.
Your husband was told that there was a risk.
Minimal risk.
Possible risk of death, wasn’t that one?
Yes. It wasn’t something…
the message was that this operation was safe, Mr. Bradford.
Please understand just how sorry I am for your loss.
Mrs. Riley, who is the first person to suggest you
that Doctor Stiles might’ve been negligent?
First person?
Yes.
Well, I am afraid I don’t really understand the question.
Well, let me state it another way: was it a doctor or was it a lawyer?
Objection!
What’s the point, Mr. Bradford?
Well, Your Honour, there are those cases where a doctor says negligence
and the plaintiff then engages a lawyer
and then there are other cases where a lawyer declares negligence
and doctors then round it up to bolsterthe claim.
Objection!
Rephrase it, Counsel.
Mrs. Riley, just how many firms did you go to
before finally one wanted to take your case?
Objection!
Sidebar? Your Honour.
Part of our defence is this is a ** claim manufactured
to flush out the deep pocket of the insurance company.
And it certainly relevant that
other attorneys decline to even take on the matter.
It’s certainly not relevant.
How other lawyer assess this has nothing to do with the case.
I agree. You are shut down there, Mr. Bradford.
Step back.
Members of the jury,
whether or not other attorneys or law firms
elected to represent the plaintiff in this matter is without relevance,
and you are to disregard the defence counsel’s question.
Let me see if I understand this:
You learned during the trial from your client
that it was his son that killed the woman.
I learned just before closing arguments, yes.
Then why didn’t you go to the District Attorney right then and ask him…
Because my client wouldn’t let me.
It was attorney-client privilege and he was looking to protect his son.
I see.
And if your client had been acquitted, that would’ve been the end of it.
Well…
You wouldn’t be here today seeking justice, would you, counsel?
That would’ve been the end of it.
Your Honour, my meeting with the boy
though he didn’t flat out admit that he did it,
he didn’t deny it either.
And a failure to deny
can constitute an admission under the rule of evidence.
The courts don’t simply throw out convictions, counsel.
Simply because…
The kid hung himself. What does that say?
I confronted him on what he did, he goes home and hung himself.
That isn’t evidence.
Then let me offer evidence.
You haven’t got any, Jimmy.
I would like the court to hear from my client.
It seems like a waste of the court’s time.
He’s serving a life sentence, we can't waste one afternoon?
One day.
I don’t know what you really plan to accomplish.
I plan to accomplish getting him out of prison which he should be.
Yeah right. Look, how about we get together on Miller?
Fine, corporate with me on Olson and I will talk to Miller.
Don’t insult my intelligence, Jimmy.
I was insulting your integrity.
Fluid is actually being pumped into the body at this point.
It’s pretty much a sole solution containing a local anesthetic.
What kind of anesthetic?
Lidocaine. It numbs the patient.
Is this a difficult procedure, doctor?
It’s quite simple actually, which is part of the problem.
We’ve got dentist doing it, dermatologist.
It’s lucrative and a lot of doctors want in
and if they are not careful
the procedure can be lethal as it was in this case.
What happened to Moris Riley?
The first mistake was taking so much fat out
anything over 15 percent in my view is unsafe.
Is this what killed him?
No.
In my opinion, Mr. Riley suffered from a lidocaine over dose.
The lidocaine lowered the heart rate eventually causing cardiac arrest.
And since he did this in his office instead of at the hospital,
he didn’t have the necessary technology
or personal available to respond to the crisis.
You weren’t in the room, were you, Dr. Willis?
No, I was not.
Have you ever preformed a lipo suction procedure, sir?
Have done hundreds.
Hundreds. Any in your office?
Almost all of them.
I see.
So this decision not to go into a hospital
you make that decision all the time.
I would never take that much fat out in my office.
If I were going to remove more 12 pounds
I would have done it in a hospital.
That’s a very good answer, doctor.
Can you state to a medical certainty
that Mr. Riley died from a lidocaine over dose?
I can state it to a reasonable certainty.
But not to an absolute medical certainty.
That can almost never be done, counsel.
I see.
And have you ever known hearts to go into arrest during this procedure
absent a lidocaine over dose?
Off course.
That’s possible here, isn’t it, doctor?
Possible. But my opinion is they over loaded him with fluids.
I see.
Tell me, doctor, how many trials have you testified in over the last year?
Many.
Many? More than 50?
Around 50.
And would it be fair to say, sir,
that you are primarily hired by these types of plaintiff law firm?
Objection!
Sustained.
Let me rephrase: you’ve been hired by this law firm before,
haven’t you, sir?
Objection! What’s the relevance?
It goes to bias, Your Honour.
He’s been hired in the past and will be hired in the future.
This witness has incentive to satisfy personal injury law firm.
Objection! Move to strike that.
I am gonna overrule the objection.
But I am closing the door on this line of questioning.
In that case I am done, Your Honour.
You know what’s going on, he’s putting us on trial.
He wants the jury to associate this case with you and me.
All I can tell you this time
is that the suspect passed the psychiatric exam
which means he’s competent to stand trial.
Was the baseball bat found…
I am not gonna comment on the evidence at this time.
When there is further developments, I will keep you apprised.
Were you surprised that this case's assigned to you
after so many recent high profile flops?
There is no strategy here, just speak from the heart.
Okay, will I have to get into the…er…
Bugs. You might.
You may have to open yourself up in there, Henry.
Our only chance is with the Judge believes you.
If he thinks you are hiding anything…
Okay.
Should Allison be there?
It couldn’t hurt.
Everything was going fine and then suddenly
his blood pressure just plunged
Did you know why?
No. there is always a risk in any surgery.
I do know we didn’t over load fluid.
When Mr. Riley’s heart went into arrest, what did you do?
We massaged the chest, brought in the defibrillator,
started the heart again;
but then it stopped.
We wheeled in a crash cart.
Contradict to Dr. Willis’assertion
we did have the technology to respond to this crisis.
Dr. Stiles, Mr. Riley did die on your table.
I know.
And it was devastating for all of us.
But death is a risk in every surgery.
Sometimes whether it would be heart failure or reaction of anesthesia,
unforeseen circumstances take a life.
All I can assure you of, as I’ve assured Mrs. Riley,
is that everything was done right in that room.
This is not a death due to doctor error.
Did you have a cardiopathic surgeon?
I beg your pardon.
Somebody who could open up the patient’s chest, ** the heart;
maybe put him on bypass either.
Did you have such a doctor in your office?
No.
A hospital would have, right?
How long have you been preforming lipo suction, sir?
I’ve been doing it for about two years.
You are a cosmetic surgeon
who specialize on face reconstruction, aren’t you?
If you are suggesting that I am not qualified to do the procedure…
I am suggesting this isn’t your specialty.
I am suggesting that up until two years ago
you worked on faces and burnt victims
but you didn’t do lipo suction, isn’t that correct?
I am sorry. I have to object to this assault.
This is an assault?
Your Honour, I have a personal affection to Mr. Young,
I think he is a fine attorney.
But perhaps I'll remind that this is a civil trial.
Your Honour.
Never mind. I am overruling the objection.
Mr. Young, proceed.
You sucked out 22 pounds of fat, didn’t you, doctor?
Yes.
You are aware that’s more than what’s considered to be safe.
You can’t quantify safety with statistics.
It’s done on a case by case basis
and in this case, I felt it was safe.
And he died.
Not because I took out too much fat.
Well… as I understand it
the more fat you suction out
the more trauma to the body, is that correct?
Yes.
And the more lidocaine need to…
This patient did not died from a lidocaine over dose.
You know that to a medical certainty?
As I said, you can never know anything to a medical certainty.
Then why are you saying it with a certainty?
Objection!
Withdrawn.
How much do you charge for this kind of procedure?
I charged Mr. Riley $8,000.
That is upfront, right? No insurance to deal with?
How is this relevant?
It is relevant because you are in the business
of sucking fat out of people without any concern…
Objection!
You could save your personal affection, Mr. Bradford.
All right.
This is a court of law, not a street fight.
What did you say?
That’s enough.
Your Honour, I apologize both to you and the jury
for this unnecessary acrimony.
Mr. Young, return your attention to the witness, please.
Mr. Olson,
at trial you said when you came out of your office
you found the woman dead,
did you see anything else?
Yes.
I saw my son Steven, he was leaving.
Your son Steven.
Yes.
But you never told anybody.
I told you deep into the trial
only because you were going to accuse my wife.
Why did you keep this secret?
He had his whole life ahead of him, Your honour.
Me?
I am…
I was a perverted deviant
who like to watch women step on bugs.
I am the reason that he committed this crime.
I drove him to commit this crime.
He'd heard his mother and me arguing about my fetish.
My attorneys told me that I had a chance of winning a trial.
So I took the chance, figuring if I could get out of prison
I could get Steven some help.
Why should we believe you?
Because I am telling the truth.
Now your son is dead, he can’t defend himself to this charges.
I told Mr. Berluti before he was dead.
Even if you did,
all of this coincides with your motive to be cleared of this crime.
And all we have is your word here,
isn’t that right, Mr. Olson?
You lied to you wife about this bug thing,
you kept the truth from your own attorneys
that is if the state of this version is the truth.
We have a conviction here supported by evidence,
would you trying to overturn with nothing but your word of honour?
And my affidavit.
I accused the son Steven of killing this woman.
He didn’t deny it, instead he goes home and kills himself.
We have a tremendous injustice here.
An innocent man is sitting in jail for a crime he didn’t commit.
We can just sit back and say too late, game is over.
It’s not too late.
There he still sits, it’s not too late.
We all say better to let ten guilty men go free
than send one innocent man to jail.
And still he sits in prison innocent.
He didn’t kill that woman.
Mr. Berluti, I am impressed with your passion
and I don’t dismiss the value of your affidavit
but still we have a process here.
The jury listened to every witness,
they deliberated it and they returned a verdict.
And I certainly have to have
more than the defendant’s word and the attorney’s word
that he’s innocent.
Otherwise I would be making a mockery of the jury system altogether.
It's one thing if the DA was coming forward with you
saying an injustice has been done.
But here,
all I have is you;
the man’s lawyer, the man’s friend,
protesting his innocence.
The conviction stands. Adjourned.
Come on, Jimmy.
I think we should call him on it.
How can we just sit back…
We stick to the case, Rebecca.
Well he’s not, you know he’s not.
We play any other card at this point, we just looked desperate.
We stick to the merit of the case.
You are wasting your time, Jimmy.
What? You think you can liquoring me up…
Suppose I deliver the Rabbi killer, murder two.
Clyde Miller for Henry Olson, straight out.
First of all, what you are proposing is so unethical.
Which is why I never proposed.
Second, I don’t need any favors on Miller, we got the guy.
No, you don’t, Richard.
Prints on the bat, Rabbi’s DNA all over…
Well he found the Rabbi dead in the alley, decided to rob him.
Is that his story?
Could be.
And you can’t completely disprove it.
The guy’s got an assault record as long as…
Yeah, history of mugging not killing.
All we need is one lone juror.
High profile case, public outrage.
You lose this one, Richard.
I know you don’t wanna think about that.
I won’t lose it, Jimmy.
Save your breath trying to intimidate me.
I got an innocent man and a way to make things easy for you.
It’s win-win, justice-justice.
If, I say if, Olson passes a polygraph,
I will consider a joined recommendation to the court.
On a completely unrelated matter
I am offering Clyde Miller murder two.
Res Ipsa Loquitor,
that’s a Latin term which basically means
what happened speaks for itself.
And that’s what we have here.
That man was an exclusive controller of the situation.
The patient died in a procedure where injury does not normally occur.
After going into a lipo suction, a procedure so simple,
dentists are now doing it,
he came out dead and the doctor’s response is
sometimes it happens, patients die.
And you know why he died, ladies and gentlemen?
Money. Money.
With HMOs cutting costs,
with hospital slashing doctor salaries,
surgeons are turning to cosmetic surgery to hit their pools.
Forget having to wait for insurance reimbursements
these procedures aren’t covered by insurance.
The money is upfront.
6, 7, 8 thousand dollars out of pop for lipo suction.
We are talking about cash, people.
And they do it right in their offices,
coz you start cutting profits when you do it in a hospital
which is okay when things go right I guess.
But when things go wrong,
Moris Riley, death.
He took out 22 pounds of fat, too much by medical standards.
He had to load him with extra lidocaine in order to do it.
Lidocaine, a drug to slow the pulse,
a drug that affects the heart.
And he did it in his office
with no cardiologist and no cardiopathic surgeon in the building
they should have been done in a hospital.
Something went terribly wrong.
Simple procedure, patient dies,
something went terribly wrong.
Res Ipsa Loquitor.
Murder two? Isn’t that like life?
It is, but with parole maybe.
If you go down on murder one, forget it.
And you don’t think that we could beat it?
OJ, he beat it.
Honest, we could take the shot,
but I don’t think we would win,
in which case you are looking at murder one.
I think if we can make this go away quiet with murder two,
you would be crazy not to take it.
Never mind there is been no negligence,
never mind nobody did anything wrong,
go to court
roll the dice and hope for a jackpot.
Didn’t used to be this way.
But with the proliferation of law schools
and the lowering of the bar if you will
we have a glut of attorneys
and a resulting boom of litigations to feed them.
Accordingly, you can always find a lawyer to take your case today,
and Mrs. Riley found two very capable ones to take hers, didn’t she?
The problem is she has no evidence
to establish any wrong doing by Doctor Stiles.
But we had an unfortunate result.
And therefore we are automatically leaping to negligence.
Mr. Young even admitted this much, didn’t he?
When he stood up here saying Res Ipsa Loquitor, let’s presume it.
I have compassion for Mr. Riley’s pani as I am sure you do.
Her husband’s heart gave out as hearts sometimes do.
There is a tragedy here, no question.
But there is no malpractice.
Mr. Young, rebuttal?
Whether there is malpractice or not, that is your decision.
But I hope you don’t think less of Mrs. Riley’s cause of action
because of the lawyers she found to represent her.
Don’t get me wrong,
like Mr. Bradford said, we are capable attorneys,
I think we are even a credit to our profession.
But let’s face it, we are not the best.
We’ve come a long way, we’ve made some progress
but we are just not the first choice, are we?
What’s going on here?
What’s going on with the proliferation of law schools
and the lowering of the bar
and more and more attorneys like us are finding our way into this room,
I am agree with you, Mr. Bradford.
Counsel, if you are not gonna argue the evidence
I will ask you to return to your seat.
Mr. Young and I are very much in evidence, Your Honour.
Mr. Bradford put us in evidence.
He asked Mrs. Riley who first told her there was negligence,
was it a doctor or was it your lawyer.
He asked how many law firms did you visited
before you found the attorney willing to take your case.
He asked our expert witness
if he was regularly hired by these types of plaintiff law firms.
He announces his personal affection for Mr. Young
and then reminds him this isn’t a street fight.
We are very much in evidence, Your Honour,
and I don’t like it.
I don’t like it one bit.
Ms. Washington, I will ask you once again
please confine your remarks to the case.
Wife saves up money to give her husband a lipo suction procedure.
They go to a doctor, doctor preforms procedure,
husband dies.
That’s a pretty good case.
Imagine how strong it would be
if Mrs. Riley had found the right kind of lawyers.
I didn’t do anything.
Where is Jimmy?
Right here. what’s…
You signed off on murder two with Clyde Miller, just like that?
We had to take it or leave it, onetime offer.
So, why did you take it?
Because he was looking at first degree…
We're still gonna trial the thing?.
And lost.
But maybe won, their evidence…
Oh, please.
Jimmy, there were no witnesses.
I’ve just beaten a much tougher case
than this one a month ago with Darrel Hutchins.
What’s going on?
Clyde Miller, he just coped to second degree.
There were no rabbits to pull on this one, Ellenor,
they had him dead to centre.
Even so, Jimmy,
that seems a little rush and since I am second chair
I think you could’ve run this by me before you...
I didn’t think you really wanted to be bothered.
Good news. Henry passed the polygraph.
He did?
Yes. They are transferring him to the court house.
What’s he taking a polygraph for?
Richard Bay, I worked him up last night
he said if Henry passed a lie detector, he'd then do us a release.
Bay’s gonna recommend a release now?
He said a polygraph would **.
Richard Bay is the DA on Clyde Miller.
Oh my god.
Tell me.
In my office.
I can’t.
They are transferring Henry back to the court house.
In my office.
Your served up Miller to get Henry out?
I made independent deals.
Don’t screw with me, Jimmy.
I made separate deals for two…
You don’t just cop to murder two.
-Judgment call and don’t tell me you’ve never done it,  -You could get disbar.
I know you’ve done it.
I am talking here.
And I am not listening, shut up.
Don’t you…
don’t you dare put yourself in my position,
a man isn’t jail coz of you.
A kid didn’t put a noose around his neck coz of you.
You are falling apart.
Of course I am falling apart.
I’ve been falling apart for three months. I…
I gotta fix this, Bobby.
I won’t let you.
You just stay the hell out of it.
I can’t. Clyde Miller is a client of this firm.
I explained it to him, he took it.
He’s stupid. He’ll do whatever you say.
You keep out of it. You wanna fire me, fire me.
But I gotta fix this.
He’s a killer. He killed a Rabbi.
He should be in jail.
Henry Olson shouldn’t be.
This is a just result.
It doesn’t work like that, Jimmy.
Please, two separate deals, two different cases.
He'd go down on murder one if we try it, just let this be.
Just let this be.
How long would it take?
It could take some time.
They first have to decide on liability,
if they find him negligent then they go to damages.
It could take some time.
You angry?
I just don’t know that you'd help, Rebecca.
It was in the air, I wasn’t playing cards, I promise.
I just had to clear some air.
This is way too fast.
Tell me about it.
Mr. Foreman, the jury has reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honour.
What say you?
On question one: do we find the defendant negligent?
We, the jury, answer:
yes.
On question two:
do we find the defendant’s negligence
to be the proximate cause of Moris Riley’s death?
We, the jury, answer:
yes.
We further order the defendant to pay damages to the plaintiff
in the amount of 6 million dollars.
Did he say…
what did he say?
He sure didn’t say 32 thousand.
Six million?
Your Honour, we move for a judgment notwithstanding the verdict
and ask it would be put aside.
Denied.
This matter is adjourned.
Members of the jury, thank you for your service.
Mr. Bay, I must say I didn’t expect this.
Your Honour, Mr. Berluti’s verified affidavit, the boy’s suicide.
I have to admit it gives me serious pause.
Then this morning Mr. Olson took a polygraph which he passed
though that’s not legally admissible,
it should certainly be deemed reliable
and well the Commonwealth no longer believes he committed the crime.
At the minimum he should be granted a new trial.
Oh, if he is granted a new trial,
will the Commonwealth pursue it?
No, Your Honour.
We couldn’t proceeding good faith at this point.
Well, then I am certainly not gonna waste anybody’s time.
Mr. Olson, you are a free man,
the conviction is set aside, you can go.
Jimmy, thank you, thank you.
Thank you.